0,S0927024813003036-2011.txt,"[38] methods, with a Sinton WCT-120 lifetime tester.","[['CARDINAL', 15, 16], ['PERSON', 21, 22]]"
1,S0927024813003036-2011.txt,"The injection level range studied varied with the lifetime of the sample, but was usually in the range 1013 cm−3 to 1016 cm−3.","[['CARDINAL', 45, 46], ['DATE', 48, 49], ['ORG', 49, 50]]"
2,S0927024813003036-2011.txt,"Boron–oxygen defects were eliminated by storing the samples in the dark after passivation, or by performing a 10 min pre-anneal at 200 °C [39] prior to lifetime measurement.","[['PERSON', 80, 81], ['CARDINAL', 100, 101], ['CARDINAL', 106, 107], ['CARDINAL', 110, 111]]"
3,S0927024813003036-2011.txt,"The samples were subjected to ∼50 close-up flashes from the lifetime tester to dissociate FeB pairs [40], after which an initial lifetime measurement was made immediately.","[['CARDINAL', 136, 137]]"
4,S0927024813003036-2011.txt,"It is noted that the aggregated illumination time of the flashes of light used to dissociate the iron–boron pairs is very short (<20  ms), so any effect on the formation of boron–oxygen defects is kept to a minimum [39].","[['CARDINAL', 197, 198]]"
5,S0927024813003036-2011.txt,"A second lifetime measurement was made more than 24 h later, which was sufficient time to reassociate the FeB pairs [19,34,41].","[['ORDINAL', 201, 202], ['CARDINAL', 206, 209]]"
6,S0927024813003036-2011.txt,"The two lifetime measurements are then analysed to give the concentration of iron that exists in FeB pairs using an established method [30,40,42].","[['CARDINAL', 226, 227], ['CARDINAL', 248, 249]]"
7,S0927024813003036-2011.txt,The specific analysis approach used is described in a previous publication [19].,"[['CARDINAL', 304, 305]]"
8,S0927024813003036-2011.txt,(1)) are used with the recombination parameters of Rein and Glunz [30] to determine the bulk iron concentration required to account for a lifetime change at a given injection level.,"[['PERSON', 328, 329], ['CARDINAL', 332, 333]]"
9,S0927024813003036-2011.txt,"For the results presented in this paper, the injection level used was 0.2p0.","[['DATE', 366, 367]]"
10,S0032386113005454-2055.txt,A double-cantilever mode at 1 Hz was employed using test specimens 60 × 10 × 3 mm3 in size.,"[['CARDINAL', 39, 40], ['CARDINAL', 46, 47]]"
11,S0032386113005454-2055.txt,The temperature range used was −100 °C to 200 °C with a heating rate of 4 °C/min.,"[['CARDINAL', 64, 65], ['CARDINAL', 72, 73]]"
12,S0032386113005454-2055.txt,"As the density of the epoxy was only measured at room temperature, the value of the front factor, q, was taken to be 0.725, as in previous work [21].","[['CARDINAL', 201, 202]]"
13,S0032386113005454-2055.txt,"The density, ρ, of the epoxy was measured at room temperature according to BS ISO 1183-1","[['ORG', 219, 224]]"
14,S0032386113005454-2055.txt,[22] to be 1.20 g/m3 at 20 °C.,"[['CARDINAL', 227, 228], ['CARDINAL', 231, 232], ['CARDINAL', 236, 237]]"
15,S0012821X12004384-1249.txt,Borehole 22/10a-4 (57°44’8.47”N; 1°50’26.59”E) provides a continuous core through the Forties Sandstone Member and into the Lista Formation (Fig. 2).,"[['CARDINAL', 1, 2], ['CARDINAL', 3, 4], ['CARDINAL', 5, 6], ['CARDINAL', 7, 8], ['CARDINAL', 9, 10], ['ORG', 16, 20], ['ORG', 22, 25], ['PERSON', 26, 27], ['CARDINAL', 28, 29]]"
16,S0012821X12004384-1249.txt,"The core consists of variably fissile claystone with interbedded fine to coarse grained sandstone layers interpreted as turbidites, with occasional mm-thick ash layers (Fig. 3).","[['ORG', 58, 59], ['CARDINAL', 60, 61]]"
17,S0012821X12004384-1249.txt,"The section of 22/10a-4 analysed in this study is from 2605 m to 2634 m (core depth), chosen because this part of the core is predominantly in claystone facies and provides a greatly expanded section over the onset of the CIE (Figs. 2 and 3).","[['CARDINAL', 85, 86], ['DATE', 92, 93], ['CARDINAL', 95, 96], ['ORG', 125, 126], ['CARDINAL', 131, 132]]"
18,S0012821X12004384-1249.txt,At 2609–2613 m the claystone becomes finely laminated with alternately pale and dark laminae couplets ranging from 1 to 25 per mm (Fig. S2).,"[['CARDINAL', 135, 136], ['CARDINAL', 151, 154], ['PERSON', 155, 156], ['PERSON', 157, 158], ['PERSON', 159, 160]]"
19,S0012821X12004384-1249.txt,Laminae were counted at 26 horizons throughout the core and approximately 13 pairs per mm.,"[['CARDINAL', 188, 189], ['CARDINAL', 194, 196], ['PERSON', 198, 199]]"
20,S0012821X13007309-1691.txt,"The Livello Bonarelli is a 1 m thick condensed interval of millimetre-laminated black shale and brown radiolarian sand that represents the sedimentary expression of part of OAE 2 (Arthur and Premoli Silva, 1982).","[['PERSON', 21, 22], ['CARDINAL', 24, 25], ['GPE', 50, 51], ['PERSON', 52, 54], ['DATE', 55, 56]]"
21,S0012821X13007309-1691.txt,"Up to 20 m beneath the Bonarelli level there are numerous centimetre scale organic-rich shale layers (Jenkyns et al., 2007).","[['CARDINAL', 58, 60], ['CARDINAL', 60, 61], ['PERSON', 64, 65], ['DATE', 82, 83]]"
22,S0012821X13007309-1691.txt,"The δ13Corg record has a narrow variation in background values prior to OAE 2, ∼−25.9 to −26.5‰. The characteristic positive excursion in δ13Corg is a 4‰ shift, −27.2 to −23.1‰, occurring within <0.5 m (Fig. 2; Supplementary Material, Table 1e).","[['ORG', 108, 109], ['CARDINAL', 111, 112], ['CARDINAL', 114, 115], ['CARDINAL', 121, 122], ['ORG', 124, 125], ['CARDINAL', 126, 127]]"
23,S0019103511004994-1399.txt,"Enceladus, one out of currently 62 satellites of Saturn, orbits the planet at a distance of 3.95 Saturn radii RS (1RS = 60,268 km) and is embedded in the radiation belts of Saturn’s inner magnetosphere.","[['NORP', 0, 1], ['CARDINAL', 2, 3], ['CARDINAL', 6, 7], ['PRODUCT', 9, 10], ['CARDINAL', 18, 19], ['PRODUCT', 19, 20], ['ORG', 21, 22], ['CARDINAL', 23, 24], ['QUANTITY', 25, 27], ['MONEY', 36, 38]]"
24,S0019103511004994-1399.txt,"Even with a small radius REnc of only 252 km and an apparent similarity to other icy moons, this moon is by far the most important internal source of dust, neutral gas and plasma in the saturnian system and especially in the magnetosphere.","[['ORG', 46, 47]]"
25,S0019103511004994-1399.txt,"As already inferred from data of the first flybys of the Pioneer 11 (1979), Voyager 1 (1980) and Voyager 2 (1981) spacecraft, respectively (Smith et al., 1981; Krimigis et al., 1982), this moon plays the same role Io does for the jovian system.","[['ORDINAL', 94, 95], ['DATE', 101, 102], ['DATE', 107, 108], ['PRODUCT', 110, 112], ['DATE', 113, 114], ['DATE', 124, 125], ['DATE', 131, 132], ['LOC', 140, 141]]"
26,S0019103511004994-1399.txt,"The Cassini spacecraft, in orbit around Saturn since July 2004, has flown by Enceladus 14 times between 2005 and 2010.","[['PERSON', 148, 149], ['PRODUCT', 154, 155], ['DATE', 156, 158], ['ORG', 162, 164], ['DATE', 165, 169]]"
27,S0019103511004994-1399.txt,"Data from Cassini instrument teams identified a plume of water geysers above the so called “tigerstripes” on the south pole of the moon (Dougherty et al., 2006; Porco et al., 2006).","[['GPE', 172, 173], ['DATE', 201, 202], ['PERSON', 203, 204], ['DATE', 208, 209]]"
28,S0019103511004994-1399.txt,This discovery is one of the most important findings to better understand the saturnian magnetosphere.,[]
29,S0019103511004994-1399.txt,"The material released in the form of water gas, ice molecules and dust (Waite et al., 2006; Spahn et al., 2006) from those geysers is the main source of the E-ring and the neutral torus and is the major plasma source of water group ions in the magnetosphere.","[['DATE', 247, 248], ['DATE', 254, 255]]"
30,S0019103511004994-1399.txt,(2009).,"[['DATE', 304, 305]]"
31,S2213671113000908-640.txt,(C) C-peptide and PDX1 expression was confirmed by immunocytochemistry of cells differentiated for 25 days.,"[['ORG', 7, 8], ['DATE', 17, 19]]"
32,S2213158213000302-1597.txt,"The MMNm component is an early (between 100 and 200 ms), automatic or largely pre-attentive response (Naatanen et al., 2007).","[['CARDINAL', 29, 33], ['LOC', 44, 45], ['DATE', 49, 50]]"
33,S2213158213000302-1597.txt,"Particularly relevant is that a prefrontal contribution to change detection also occurs within this early time window, demonstrated in Garrido and colleagues' dynamic causal modelling of a roving oddball paradigm (Garrido et al., 2008) and the effects of frontal lesions (Alho et al., 1994).","[['GPE', 72, 73], ['DATE', 104, 105]]"
34,S2213158213000302-1597.txt,"This suggests that if the prefrontal cortical dysfunction in the two patient groups is the cause of the altered network response, then this affects the very early stages of stimuli processing.","[['CARDINAL', 117, 118]]"
35,S2213158213000302-1597.txt,"Although this early component is distinct from the later M300 response, which reflects attentional processing (Wronka et al., 2008), it is still relevant to high order cognitive processes, (Naatanen et al., 2007, 2012).","[['LOC', 176, 177], ['DATE', 181, 182], ['DATE', 183, 184]]"
36,S0925443913001385-1646.txt,"In order to determine whether the MRPL12 mutation also induced changes in composition and assembly of the mitochondrial ribosomal large and small subunits, mitochondrial lysates from cultured fibroblasts (subject and control) were fractionated on isokinetic sucrose gradients (10–30%, as in Ref.","[['PERCENT', 41, 43], ['GPE', 46, 47]]"
37,S0925443913001385-1646.txt,[47]).,"[['CARDINAL', 49, 50]]"
38,S0925443913001385-1646.txt,"On analysis MRPL12 from the patient was substantially decreased in all fractions but detectable in the fractions consistent with mt-LSU; however it was noticeably absent from the free pool (fractions 1 and 2, Fig. 5).","[['CARDINAL', 114, 115], ['CARDINAL', 116, 117], ['PERSON', 118, 119], ['CARDINAL', 120, 121]]"
39,S0925443913001385-1646.txt,"This was in contrast to the control that exhibited a pool of free MRPL12, which has been reported to interact with POLRMT [56].","[['ORG', 145, 146], ['CARDINAL', 147, 148]]"
40,S0925443913001385-1646.txt,"The MRPL12 mutation impacted more modestly on the small ribosomal subunit, with DAP3 apparently unaffected and MRPS18B found in lower amounts only in fractions 4 and 5 but otherwise with similar steady state levels and distribution profile compared to control.","[['CARDINAL', 193, 194], ['CARDINAL', 195, 196]]"
41,S0925443913001385-1646.txt,"Since POLRMT and MRPL12 have been published as interactors, we analyzed both the steady state level and gradient distribution of POLRMT to see if these were affected by the MRPL12 mutation.","[['ORG', 211, 212], ['ORG', 231, 232]]"
42,S0925443913001385-1646.txt,"Overall levels in the subject sample were decreased to 63% of control value (Fig. 5B) but distribution in the gradient appeared largely unaffected with the exception of fraction 11, where levels were lower than control (Fig.","[['PERCENT', 252, 254], ['ORG', 258, 259], ['CARDINAL', 260, 261], ['DATE', 275, 276], ['PERSON', 284, 285]]"
43,S0167610513001001-739.txt,Median wind speed is 7.83 m s−1.,"[['NORP', 16, 17], ['CARDINAL', 20, 21]]"
44,S0167577X13006393-399.txt,The pure PLGA spectrum shows the C3O characteristic bands in the region 1065–1280 cm−1.,"[['NORP', 36, 37], ['CARDINAL', 46, 47]]"
45,S0167577X13006393-399.txt,"The spectrum of HA nanopowder reveals the characteristic peak assigned to PO43−: ν1 vibration mode at about 964 cm−1, ν3 vibration mode at 1031 cm−1 and 1091 cm−1 (asymmetric) respectively.","[['PERSON', 60, 61], ['CARDINAL', 66, 68], ['DATE', 74, 75], ['DATE', 77, 78]]"
46,S0167577X13006393-399.txt,The spectrum of untreated PLGA–HA 50% displays both characteristics of PLGA and HA.,"[['PERCENT', 91, 93], ['ORG', 97, 98]]"
47,S1550413113004920-1509.txt,We recruited 147 patients from consanguineous pedigrees (parents of the proband were second cousins or more closely related) who were diagnosed with permanent diabetes before 6 months of age or were diagnosed with permanent diabetes before 9 months and had any additional clinical features that made a diagnosis of type 1 diabetes less likely.,"[['CARDINAL', 2, 3], ['ORDINAL', 13, 14], ['DATE', 27, 31], ['DATE', 38, 40], ['CARDINAL', 52, 53]]"
48,S0167610512002292-3187.txt,"For each of the 7 initial orientations, a case, numbered 4 in Table 2, was run using a 0.563 m square plate of thickness 0.025 m.","[['CARDINAL', 4, 5], ['CARDINAL', 12, 13], ['QUANTITY', 21, 24], ['CARDINAL', 27, 28]]"
49,S0167610512002292-3187.txt,"The density of the plate was adjusted to ensure that at the mean horizontal wind flow, the Tachikawa number, K and Froude number Fr are the same as in the number 1 cases.","[['ORG', 47, 48], ['PERSON', 54, 55], ['CARDINAL', 62, 63]]"
50,S0167610512002292-3187.txt,"The result is two sets of cases, A1 to G1 and A4 to G4, with the same set of initial orientations, aspect ratio and flow parameter but considerably lower thickness ratio, τ=t/L, and non-dimensionalised mass moment of inertia about the Z-axis, Δzz, in the A4 to G4 cases.","[['CARDINAL', 68, 69], ['PERSON', 73, 74], ['PRODUCT', 77, 78], ['CARDINAL', 79, 80], ['PRODUCT', 124, 125], ['CARDINAL', 126, 127]]"
51,S0167610512002292-3187.txt,"Similarly a fifth case, numbered 5 in Table 2 is run for each initial orientation, and the plate's K, FrL, τ and Δzz are kept constant relative to cases numbered 4, but the width of the plate, B is increased to give a higher aspect ratio.","[['ORDINAL', 131, 132], ['CARDINAL', 135, 136], ['ORG', 150, 153], ['CARDINAL', 164, 165]]"
52,S0927024813002961-1051.txt,"Specific consideration is given to the accuracy of module inter-comparisons, as most outdoor monitoring at this scale is conducted to compare devices against one another.",[]
53,S0927024813002961-1051.txt,It is shown that there are five main contributors to differences in energy delivery and the magnitude of these depends on the environments in which the devices are operated.,"[['CARDINAL', 129, 130]]"
54,S0927024813002961-1051.txt,"The paper shows that two effects, typically not considered in inter-comparisons, dominate the reported energy delivery.","[['CARDINAL', 157, 158]]"
55,S0927024813002961-1051.txt,"Environmental influences such as light intensity, spectrum and operating temperature introduce performance variations typically in the range of 2–7% in the course of a year.","[['PERCENT', 193, 195], ['DATE', 199, 201]]"
56,S0927024813002961-1051.txt,"Here, the power rating is a key factor and adds uncertainty for new technologies such as thin films often in the range of 10–15%.","[['PERCENT', 247, 249]]"
57,S0927024813002961-1051.txt,"This dominates inter-comparisons looking at as-new, first-year energy yields, yet considering the life-time energy yield it is found that ageing causes up to 25% variation between different devices.","[['DATE', 261, 264], ['PERCENT', 283, 285]]"
58,S0019103512003995-1767.txt,"(2001) looked for absorption by species such as Na,H,He,CH+,CO+,N2+, and H2O+ in the upper atmosphere of HD209458b.","[['DATE', 5, 6], ['ORG', 14, 17], ['ORG', 24, 25]]"
59,S0019103512003995-1767.txt,(2003) who attempted to measure the transit depth in the He 1083 nm line that was predicted to be significant by Seager and Sasselov (2000).,"[['DATE', 42, 43], ['ORG', 64, 67]]"
60,S0019103512003995-1767.txt,(2004) and Narita et al.,"[['DATE', 83, 84]]"
61,S0019103512003995-1767.txt,"(2005) who looked for transits in the Na D, Li,","[['DATE', 91, 92], ['LOC', 98, 101], ['PERSON', 102, 103]]"
62,S0012821X12004384-952.txt,Carbon isotopic results of total organic matter (δ13CTOC) and amorphous organic matter (δ13CAOM) against core 22/10a-4 lithology and Apectodinium spp.,"[['CARDINAL', 19, 20]]"
63,S0012821X12004384-952.txt,Blue=bulk rock δ13CTOC; black=δ13CAOM; solid red symbols=bulk rock δ13CTOC from samples with <30% wood/plant tissue (determined from palynological residue of the sample); open red symbols=bulk rock δ13CTOC from samples with >30% wood/plant tissue.,"[['PERCENT', 50, 52], ['PERCENT', 76, 79]]"
64,S0012821X12004384-952.txt,"The first appearance of Apectodinium augustum identifies the PETM in the North Sea (Bujak and Brinkhuis, 1998), and the first negative shift in δ13C identifies the approximate position of the CIE onset and the Paleocene–Eocene boundary.","[['ORDINAL', 85, 86], ['LOC', 94, 97], ['PERSON', 98, 99], ['GPE', 100, 101], ['DATE', 102, 103], ['ORDINAL', 107, 108], ['ORG', 118, 119]]"
65,S0012821X12004384-952.txt,Values shaded at 2614.7 and 2619.6 m are considered possible outliers based on statistical analysis of the palynological residues (see Section 4.1).,"[['CARDINAL', 130, 131], ['CARDINAL', 132, 133], ['LAW', 148, 150]]"
66,S2213158213000582-1340.txt,The average percent variance explained for gradiometer data using VESTAL was 95.81% for HC and 94.38% for SZ.,"[['FAC', 53, 54], ['PERCENT', 55, 57], ['ORG', 58, 59], ['PERCENT', 60, 62], ['GPE', 63, 64]]"
67,S2213158213000582-1340.txt,The average percent variance explained for magnetometer data using VESTAL program was 96.24% for HC and 93.17% for SZ.,"[['ORG', 74, 75], ['PERCENT', 77, 79], ['ORG', 80, 81], ['PERCENT', 82, 84], ['PERSON', 85, 86]]"
68,S2213158213000582-1340.txt,"1.16, p = 0.25) or magnetometer data (t(39) = 1.31, p = 0.20).","[['CARDINAL', 103, 104], ['CARDINAL', 107, 108], ['CARDINAL', 116, 117], ['CARDINAL', 120, 121]]"
69,S0167577X14001256-389.txt,"One-dimensional composition profiles of Fe, Cr, Ni, Mo, Mn, Ti, Nb, C, Si, and P across SD 1 and SD 2 are shown in (a) and (d), respectively, and (b) and (e) show the same at higher magnification (12×).","[['CARDINAL', 0, 1], ['ORG', 6, 26], ['CARDINAL', 60, 61]]"
70,S0167577X14001256-389.txt,These elemental compositions were obtained along the arrow of 4 nm width shown in the insets in (c) and (f).,"[['CARDINAL', 72, 73]]"
71,S2211124713006475-841.txt,(O) GH plasma levels using a human specific ELISA (6 weeks after transplantation).,"[['ORG', 10, 11], ['DATE', 12, 14]]"
72,S0025322712001600-2406.txt,Estimates of mineral composition were made by a reference intensity ratio method based on factors calculated with the Newmod programme as described in Hillier (2003).,"[['ORG', 39, 40], ['DATE', 46, 47]]"
73,S0025322712001600-2406.txt,"Illite crystallinity was measured using the full width at half maximum (FHWM) of the 001 basal illite peak and integral breadth (I Breadth) of the same peak (Kübler and Jaboyedoff, 2000).","[['CARDINAL', 58, 59], ['ORG', 61, 62], ['CARDINAL', 65, 66], ['PERSON', 74, 75], ['PERSON', 81, 82]]"
74,S0025322712001600-2406.txt,"Both measurements are measured as values of ∆2°θ and show identical trends (Alizai et al., 2012).","[['DATE', 108, 109]]"
75,S0025322712001600-2406.txt,"Because our cores are < 9 m long, post-depositional burial diagenesis should not be a significant factor in clay mineral composition.","[['CARDINAL', 116, 117]]"
76,S0025322712001600-2406.txt,"Where clay mineral values are greater than 10% uncertainty is estimated as better than 5% weight at the 95% confidence level (Hillier, 2003).","[['PERCENT', 141, 145], ['PERCENT', 151, 153], ['PERCENT', 156, 158], ['DATE', 163, 164]]"
77,S0025322712001600-2406.txt,Clay mineral estimates are shown in Table 1.,"[['LAW', 172, 174]]"
78,S0012821X12004384-1232.txt,"As 22/10a-4 is in the deep (>0.5 km) central part of the basin, it acted as a depocentre and exhibits a Paleocene-Eocene transition sequence that is not only expanded but is also close to being stratigraphically complete.","[['CARDINAL', 1, 2], ['QUANTITY', 8, 10], ['ORG', 25, 28]]"
79,S0012821X12004384-1232.txt,The only evidence for breaks in the succession is minor erosion at the base of thin turbidite sandstones (typically <10 cm).,"[['QUANTITY', 65, 67]]"
80,S0012821X12004384-1232.txt,"During the late Paleocene, the basin became restricted following a fall in in the order of 100 m that resulted from regional uplift associated with the proto-Iceland mantle plume in the North Atlantic (see Knox, 1996).","[['PERSON', 88, 89], ['CARDINAL', 102, 103], ['LOC', 118, 121], ['ORG', 123, 124], ['DATE', 125, 126]]"
81,S0012821X12004384-1232.txt,"This event is evident in 22/10a-4 as a lithologic change from unbedded to bedded mudstone (the Lista and Sele Formation boundary, Fig. 2).","[['CARDINAL', 133, 134], ['ORG', 145, 146], ['PERSON', 147, 149], ['PERSON', 151, 152], ['CARDINAL', 153, 154]]"
82,S0012821X12004384-1232.txt,"Restriction of the basin also led to the establishment of poorly oxygenated bottom waters, as is evident by a shift in the benthic foraminiferal assemblages towards low diversity low oxygen-tolerant agglutinated species (Knox, 1996).","[['ORG', 192, 193], ['DATE', 194, 195]]"
83,S0012821X12004384-1232.txt,"The CIE at the Paleocene–Eocene boundary was accompanied by a relative sea level rise, as documented in southeast England (Powell et al., 1996) and Spitsbergen (Harding et al., 2011), due to the thermal expansion of sea water and possible melting of ice caps, although the North Sea basin remained restricted as evidenced by the persistence of low oxygen facies in 22/10a-4.","[['ORG', 198, 199], ['GPE', 218, 219], ['PERSON', 220, 221], ['DATE', 225, 226], ['ORG', 228, 229], ['DATE', 235, 236], ['LOC', 255, 257], ['DATE', 270, 271]]"
84,S0012821X12004384-1232.txt,"The North Sea had a widespread freshwater catchment area, and a halocline was in place from the late Paleocene to early Eocene (Zacke et al., 2009).","[['LOC', 272, 275], ['DATE', 301, 302]]"
85,S2213671113000738-684.txt,"In sequential PET studies, we observed increased uptake of [11C]PK11195 in one allograft (animal No. 10) at 3 months (Figures 3A and 3B).","[['ORG', 2, 3], ['CARDINAL', 13, 14], ['CARDINAL', 19, 20], ['DATE', 22, 24], ['CARDINAL', 26, 27]]"
86,S2213671113000738-684.txt,"Intriguingly, the serum level of IFN-γ temporarily increased at 2 months after the transplant in three animals (Figure 3C).","[['ORG', 59, 60], ['DATE', 65, 67], ['CARDINAL', 71, 72]]"
87,S2213671113000738-684.txt,"An immunofluorescence study conducted at 3.5–4 months showed that MHC-II+ cells were more frequently found in allografts than in autografts, especially in the monkey with increased uptake of [11C]PK11195 (Figure 3D, No. 10).","[['DATE', 83, 85], ['CARDINAL', 117, 118]]"
88,S2213671113000738-684.txt,"The MHC-II staining never overlapped with that of GFP of the donor cells (Figure 3F), whereas it generally overlapped with that of IBA1 (Figure 3G), indicating that MHC-II was expressed by host-derived microglia.","[['ORG', 130, 131], ['CARDINAL', 137, 138], ['GPE', 147, 148], ['CARDINAL', 150, 151]]"
89,S2213671113000738-684.txt,An immunofluorescence study revealed that more CD45+ cells (a marker for pan-leukocytes) accumulated in allografts compared with autografts (Figures 3I and 3J).,"[['PRODUCT', 220, 221], ['CARDINAL', 239, 240]]"
90,S2213671113000738-684.txt,"Most of the CD45+ cells were CD3+ T cells, and 60% of them were CD8+ killer T cells (Figures 3K and 3L).","[['PRODUCT', 247, 248], ['PERCENT', 257, 259], ['CARDINAL', 269, 271], ['CARDINAL', 272, 273]]"
91,S0012821X12004384-1221.txt,"During the late Paleocene–early Eocene the North Sea was a restricted marine basin, characterised by siliciclastic sedimentation and high terrigenous input, principally from the Scotland–Faeroe–Shetland landmass (Knox 1998, Fig.","[['LOC', 7, 10], ['GPE', 28, 29], ['DATE', 35, 37], ['PERSON', 38, 39]]"
92,S0012821X12004384-1221.txt,Core 22/10a-4 is located in the central part of the basin (Figs. 1 and S1) and is therefore disconnected from many marginal marine processes that could mask oceanographic signals (e.g. tidal or storm-induced erosion and slumping).,"[['PERSON', 43, 45]]"
93,S0012821X12004384-1221.txt,"Paleobathymetry estimates in the North Sea during the Paleocene and Eocene are difficult to constrain accurately, as the extant benthic foraminifera present in the Paleogene are found today living between 200 and >1000 m water depth (Gradstein et al., 1992), and are controlled predominantly by substrate and bottom water properties.","[['LOC', 90, 93], ['PERSON', 97, 98], ['PERSON', 112, 113], ['DATE', 115, 116], ['CARDINAL', 117, 122], ['PERSON', 126, 127], ['DATE', 131, 132]]"
94,S0012821X12004384-1221.txt,"However using a number of paleoecologic micropaleontology methods together (Gillmore et al., 2001), along with 2D structural restoration (Kjennerud and Sylta, 2001), broad agreement was found and central parts of the northern North Sea appear to have had paleodepths of >0.5 km in the earliest Eocene near 22/10a-4 (Kjennerud and Gillmore, 2003, Fig.","[['DATE', 160, 161], ['CARDINAL', 165, 166], ['ORG', 169, 170], ['GPE', 171, 172], ['DATE', 173, 174], ['LOC', 186, 188], ['QUANTITY', 195, 197], ['PERSON', 200, 201], ['DATE', 202, 203], ['ORG', 204, 207], ['DATE', 208, 209], ['PERSON', 210, 211]]"
95,S1359835X13001875-1359.txt,"Our model consists of a two-dimensional square system, with pre-set side length of L = 1 m, containing N = 1000 discrete particles.","[['CARDINAL', 5, 6], ['CARDINAL', 20, 21], ['CARDINAL', 26, 27]]"
96,S1359835X13001875-1359.txt,"The overall coverage of particles in the material is given by the number density, λ = N/L2 (fixed at 1000 m−2) and the area fraction, Af=λa¯, where a¯ is the mean cross-sectional area of a particle.","[['ORG', 47, 50]]"
97,S1359835X13001875-1359.txt,Periodic boundary conditions are applied to the edges of the system to reduce finite size effects [22].,"[['CARDINAL', 95, 96]]"
98,S0006322312001096-1248.txt,"After adjustment for multiple covariates (age, sex, marital status, education, socioeconomic status, retirement, cognitive impairment, body mass index, alcohol consumption, menopausal status [women], and nonvascular chronic condition), the association between vascular disease and subsequent CES-D depressive symptoms remained in participants with no prevalent or previous depressive episodes, as indicated by the Composite International Diagnostic Interview (Table 3).","[['ORG', 68, 75]]"
99,S0006322312001096-1248.txt,"Higher stroke risk score was associated with higher odds of onset of CES-D depressive symptoms before (odds ratio 2.30, 95% CI 1.03–5.13), but not after, the age 65.","[['CARDINAL', 99, 100], ['PERCENT', 101, 103], ['CARDINAL', 104, 105], ['DATE', 111, 114]]"
100,S0006322312001096-1278.txt,"However, although the stroke risk score was associated with depressive symptoms before the age of 65, we found little evidence to suggest that standard clinical information on preclinical vascular risk status would be helpful in the prediction of depressive symptoms after the age of 65 years.","[['DATE', 66, 70], ['DATE', 96, 101]]"
101,S1750583613004192-714.txt,"The Sleipner plume profile, viewed from the southeast, circa July 2002.","[['PERSON', 1, 2], ['DATE', 11, 13]]"
102,S1750583613004192-714.txt,"The figure shows the distribution of injected CO2 after 5 Mt of injected CO2 (Bickle et al., 2007).","[['CARDINAL', 23, 24], ['ORG', 27, 32], ['DATE', 34, 35]]"
103,S1750583613004192-714.txt,"The nine plume layers are well defined aerially, having ponded beneath intra-formational shales within the Utsira Sand.","[['CARDINAL', 38, 39]]"
104,S1750583613004192-714.txt,"The ninth layer first appeared in 1999, indicating that the CO2 has migrated approximately 220 m vertically from the injection point (IP) at 1012 mbsl in 3 years.","[['ORDINAL', 68, 69], ['ORDINAL', 70, 71], ['DATE', 73, 74], ['CARDINAL', 82, 83], ['ORG', 90, 91], ['DATE', 93, 94], ['DATE', 96, 98]]"
105,S1750583613004192-714.txt,"The left panel is a regional stratigraphic column: MSL, Mean Sea Level; SWI, Sediment Water Interface; The Nordland Group extends from the caprock to seafloor, and is subdivided into three seals: US, Upper Seal (Pleistocene); MS, Middle Seal (Upper Pliocene); LS, Lower Seal (Upper Pliocene); Utsira, storage site (Middle Miocene–Early Pliocene); HG, Hordland Group (Early Miocene).","[['LOC', 110, 113], ['ORG', 114, 115], ['ORG', 116, 119], ['ORG', 120, 123], ['CARDINAL', 134, 135], ['GPE', 137, 138], ['ORG', 175, 176], ['ORG', 177, 179]]"
106,S0006322312001096-1197.txt,We used three indicators (or proxy measures) to identify persons with depressive symptoms.,"[['CARDINAL', 2, 3]]"
107,S0006322312001096-1197.txt,"First, participants responded to the self-administered 30-item General Health Questionnaire (GHQ) at phases 3, 5, 7, and 9, a screening instrument designed for and widely used in population-based surveys and trials (26).","[['ORDINAL', 16, 17], ['CARDINAL', 25, 26], ['CARDINAL', 36, 37], ['DATE', 38, 39], ['DATE', 40, 41], ['CARDINAL', 43, 44], ['CARDINAL', 61, 62]]"
108,S0006322312001096-1197.txt,"Each questionnaire item enquires about a specific symptom, with response categories scored as either 1 or 0 to indicate whether the symptom is present.","[['CARDINAL', 79, 80]]"
109,S0006322312001096-1197.txt,Total score of 5 or more led to individuals being defined as GHQ-symptom cases and scores 0 to 4 as noncases (27).,"[['CARDINAL', 93, 94], ['CARDINAL', 108, 111], ['CARDINAL', 114, 115]]"
110,S0006322312001096-1197.txt,"Although the GHQ was originally designed to assess depressive and anxiety symptoms, a recent population-based study showed GHQ caseness to be sensitive (84%) and specific (84%) in detecting dysthymia or major depressive disorder, as indicated by the Composite International Diagnostic Interview (28).","[['ORG', 119, 120], ['ORG', 137, 138], ['PERCENT', 143, 145], ['PERCENT', 149, 151], ['ORG', 163, 168], ['CARDINAL', 169, 170]]"
111,S0006322312001096-1197.txt,"The GHQ has also been validated at baseline against a clinical interview schedule in the Whitehall II study, with acceptable sensitivity (73%) and specificity (78%) (27).","[['ORG', 173, 174], ['PERCENT', 195, 197], ['PERCENT', 201, 203], ['CARDINAL', 205, 206]]"
112,S0006322312001096-1197.txt,"In a more recent validation using a subgroup of 274 participants aged 58 to 70 in 2010, the sensitivity and specificity of GHQ symptom caseness against diagnosed depressive episodes based on a structured psychiatric interview were 80% and 81%, respectively.","[['CARDINAL', 217, 218], ['DATE', 220, 223], ['DATE', 224, 225], ['PERCENT', 245, 250]]"
113,S0378383912000130-3745.txt,"For the 8.5 mm beach the modelling produces a reasonably accurate trend at x = 1980 mm, while at x = 2780 mm the model fails to predict the initial sharp rise and the decline at the later stages of the swash.","[['QUANTITY', 2, 4], ['DATE', 15, 16], ['DATE', 22, 23]]"
114,S0378383911001669-1112.txt,"Depth time-series at all six measurement locations for the 1.3 mm sand-rough (-), the 5.4 mm gravel-rough (--) and the 8.4 mm gravel-rough (-.-.) beaches.","[['CARDINAL', 6, 7], ['QUANTITY', 11, 13], ['QUANTITY', 21, 23], ['QUANTITY', 31, 33]]"
115,S0006322312001096-1205.txt,"Third, at phases 3, 5, 7, and 9, participants were asked whether they had taken any medication in the past 14 days and, if so, to provide the name of the medication.","[['ORDINAL', 0, 1], ['CARDINAL', 4, 5], ['DATE', 6, 7], ['DATE', 8, 9], ['CARDINAL', 11, 12], ['DATE', 23, 27]]"
116,S0006322312001096-1205.txt,Medications were coded using British National Formulary codes to define antidepressant medication use (codes: 040301–040304) (31).,"[['ORG', 44, 47], ['CARDINAL', 56, 57], ['CARDINAL', 59, 60]]"
117,S1359645413009816-2973.txt,"From high-resolution transmission electron microscopy, values for Au of eGB=(0.04–0.10)×10-10m (Ref.","[['CARDINAL', 38, 41], ['ORG', 43, 44]]"
118,S1359645413009816-2973.txt,[22]) or eGB=0.12×10-10m (Ref.,"[['CARDINAL', 46, 47], ['ORG', 55, 56]]"
119,S1359645413009816-2973.txt,[23]) are reported.,"[['CARDINAL', 58, 59]]"
120,S1359645413009816-2973.txt,"From measurements of the grain boundary contact angle in an Al tricrystal, a value eGB=0.64×10-10m is reported by Shvindlerman et al.","[['ORG', 79, 80], ['PERSON', 86, 87]]"
121,S1359645413009816-2973.txt,[24] applying a thermodynamic model.,"[['CARDINAL', 91, 92]]"
122,S1359645413009816-2973.txt,"For nanocrystalline Pd [25] and Fe [26], values of eGB=0.23×10-10m and 0.19×10-10m were determined from density measurements and modeling of grain growth kinetics, respectively.","[['CARDINAL', 102, 103], ['CARDINAL', 107, 108], ['ORG', 112, 115], ['CARDINAL', 117, 120]]"
123,S1359645413009816-2973.txt,A number of computer simulations of grain boundaries [27–30] deal with the issue of grain boundary expansion.,"[['CARDINAL', 144, 145]]"
124,S1359645413009816-2973.txt,"Here, however, the choice of the interatomic potentials was found to have a substantial influence on the numerical results [27].","[['CARDINAL', 177, 178]]"
125,S1359645413009816-2973.txt,"Most recently, grain boundary expansion data have been reported from molecular dynamics simulations on Ni, eGB=(0.28–0.42)×10-10m for random high-angle grain boundaries [30] and eGB=(0.39–0.41)×10-10m (at T = 1200 K) for Σ5 grain boundaries [29].","[['ORG', 195, 196], ['CARDINAL', 197, 200], ['CARDINAL', 209, 210], ['CARDINAL', 228, 229]]"
126,S0019103512002801-2018.txt,"(2012) demonstrates that the combination of low magnetosonic Mach number and the high plasma beta values of Rhea’s space environment amplifies interaction features which for other plasma absorbers (e.g. Tethys, Dione, Earth’s Moon) are barely detectable.","[['DATE', 42, 43], ['PERSON', 51, 52], ['ORG', 60, 62], ['WORK_OF_ART', 73, 77]]"
127,S0019103512002801-2018.txt,"One of these features is a stronger, flow-aligned magnetic field component perturbation, which gives rise to mass-loading-like interaction signatures.","[['CARDINAL', 86, 87]]"
128,S0019103512002801-2018.txt,"Similarly, the high plasma beta makes surface charging more important for Rhea compared to the other Saturnian moons (Roussos et al., 2010).","[['PERSON', 142, 143], ['NORP', 147, 148], ['DATE', 155, 156]]"
129,S0019103512002801-2018.txt,"Furthermore, recent developments in the study of Earth’s Moon interaction with the solar wind indicate that the standard picture for a lunar-type interaction may be too simplified: processes, such as the entry of exospheric pick-up ions in the center of the wake, backscattering on the surface and self-pick up of ambient plasma ions, appear to also have an impact on the wake dynamics (Halekas et al., 2011).","[['LOC', 166, 169], ['DATE', 239, 240]]"
130,S0019103512002801-2018.txt,"For instance, the self-pick up process has been shown to lead to enhanced ULF wave activity in the lunar, at least 10% of the time (Nakagawa et al., 2012).","[['ORG', 258, 259], ['PERCENT', 265, 269], ['GPE', 273, 274], ['DATE', 278, 279]]"
131,S2213671113001306-907.txt,"(A) Fetal hRPE stained for pan-cytokeratin (scale bar, 50 μm); inset shows section overview stained with hematoxylin/eosin (scale bar, 200 μm).","[['CARDINAL', 14, 15], ['CARDINAL', 31, 32]]"
132,S0165587612003680-1078.txt,"S. pneumoniae, M. catarrhalis and H. influenzae are the most common pathogens implicated in OME, and all are capable of forming biofilms [33,42].","[['ORG', 0, 1], ['ORG', 15, 16]]"
133,S0165587612003680-1078.txt,"However, rather than focusing just on those three bacteria, this study cultured effusions on a wide range of different media for prolonged time periods in order to capture as many isolates as possible.","[['CARDINAL', 36, 37]]"
134,S0165587612003680-1078.txt,and S. aureus were the three commonest pathogens isolated in this study.,"[['ORG', 77, 78], ['CARDINAL', 81, 82]]"
135,S0165587612003680-1078.txt,"CoNS were long thought to be non-pathogenic commensals, but with the recognition of their biofilm-forming capacity have emerged as the leading cause of biomaterials-related infection [43,43].",[]
136,S0165587612003680-1078.txt,"S. lugdunensis, isolated here on three occasions, in particular has been implicated in endocarditis, wound infection, and implant-related infection as well as otitis media, behaving more like S. aureus than other CoNS [45].","[['CARDINAL', 131, 132], ['LOC', 163, 164], ['CARDINAL', 165, 166]]"
137,S0165587612003680-1078.txt,"Other CoNS have also been previously implicated in otitis media, with a recent study finding that they account for 60% of bacteria isolated from OME [46,47].","[['PERCENT', 188, 190], ['ORG', 194, 195]]"
138,S0165587612003680-1078.txt,"Veillonella is a Gram-negative anaerobe that inhabits the mouth and upper respiratory tract, forms biofilms [48] and has previously been found in middle ear disease [49,50].","[['CARDINAL', 218, 219]]"
139,S0165587612003680-1078.txt,"S. aureus also forms biofilms and has been identified in middle ear disease [51,52].",[]
140,S0165587612003680-1078.txt,"Although most of the bacteria in Table 2 have previously been isolated in middle ear disease, to the best of the authors’ knowledge Flavimonas oryzihabitans, Vibrio metschnikovii and Gemella haemolysans have not been implicated previously.","[['LAW', 256, 258], ['ORG', 275, 276], ['PERSON', 278, 279], ['ORG', 281, 282]]"
141,S0019103513005058-4175.txt,"The nominal range (1.0–1.7 wt.% SO4) is consistent with 1.3 wt.% soluble sulfate measured at the Phoenix landing site (Kounaves et al., 2010b).","[['EVENT', 25, 28], ['CARDINAL', 32, 33], ['GPE', 39, 40], ['DATE', 48, 49]]"
142,S0019103513005058-4175.txt,"The estimates also compare well with an average ∼6.8 wt.% sulfur as SO3 (2.7 wt.% S) in global soil inferred from elemental abundances measured at various locations on Mars by Spirit, Opportunity, Pathfinder, and Viking Landers.","[['LOC', 81, 82], ['ORG', 85, 86], ['PERSON', 87, 88], ['PERSON', 90, 92]]"
143,S0019103513005058-4175.txt,"We can also compare the average sulfur content in the top few tens of centimeters of the soil of ∼4.4 wt.% inferred from Gamma Ray Spectrometer measurements (King and McLennan, 2010).","[['ORG', 112, 114], ['PERSON', 116, 119], ['DATE', 125, 126]]"
144,S0019103513005058-4175.txt,The agreement between model results and data suggest that 0.1% of the terrestrial volcanic gas flux is a good estimate for the volcanic emission rate on Mars 1–2 Ga if soil salts derive from volcanic input.,"[['PERCENT', 137, 139], ['LOC', 155, 157]]"
145,S0019103511004994-996.txt,"The energy is mentioned on the top of each figure, The parameter a = 0.1 is the assumed surface velocity of 10% relative to the upstream velocity.","[['CARDINAL', 51, 52], ['PERCENT', 58, 60]]"
146,S0378112713005288-2062.txt,"While we might expect seedlings from larger seeded species like rowan (200,000 seeds weigh 1 kg) to have an advantage over seedlings from smaller seeded species such as birch (5.9 million seeds weigh 1 kg) in growing through brash (Leishman and Westoby, 1994) we found no significant difference between the proportion of rowan in windrows and interrows.","[['CARDINAL', 61, 62], ['QUANTITY', 64, 66], ['CARDINAL', 81, 83], ['QUANTITY', 85, 87], ['ORG', 93, 96], ['DATE', 97, 98]]"
147,S0378112713005288-2062.txt,"Furthermore, previous studies have found that where grazing pressure is high, brash (Truscott et al., 2004) and coarse woody debris (Smit et al., 2012) can help protect seedlings from browsing.","[['DATE', 134, 135], ['DATE', 146, 147]]"
148,S0378112713005288-2062.txt,"The low incidence of browsing at our study sites (grazing pressure was controlled) means that grazing is unlikely to limit regeneration (Palmer et al., 2004; Olesen and Madsen, 2008; Yamagawa et al., 2010).","[['DATE', 208, 209], ['ORG', 212, 215], ['PERSON', 216, 217], ['DATE', 221, 222]]"
149,S1873506113001116-978.txt,Large-scale production of human induced pluripotent stem cells (hiPSCs) by robust and economic methods has been one of the major challenges for translational realization of hiPSC technology.,[]
150,S1873506113001116-978.txt,"Serial passaging of two different hiPSC lines in the spinner flasks using the E8 medium preserved their normal karyotype and expression of undifferentiated state markers of TRA-1–60, SSEA4, OCT4, and NANOG.","[['CARDINAL', 87, 88], ['CARDINAL', 97, 98], ['NORP', 110, 111], ['ORG', 112, 113], ['ORG', 114, 115], ['ORG', 117, 118]]"
151,S1873506113001116-978.txt,"The hiPSCs cultured in spinner flasks for more than 10 passages not only could be remained pluripotent as indicated by in vitro and in vivo assays, but also could be efficiently induced toward mesodermal and hematopoietic differentiation.","[['CARDINAL', 120, 121], ['CARDINAL', 126, 129], ['DATE', 144, 145]]"
152,S0378383912000130-3755.txt,"Moreover, hydraulic gradients are significantly reduced by the build-up of pore-air pressure in the unsaturated region of the 1.5 mm beach (Steenhauer et al., 2011a).","[['QUANTITY', 64, 66], ['NORP', 68, 69], ['DATE', 73, 74]]"
153,S0378383912000130-3755.txt,This pressure build-up is discussed in Section 3.3.,"[['LAW', 84, 86]]"
154,S1570870512000637-1206.txt,[42] believe that the natural evolution of the Internet should be to harness multipath-capable end systems in order to achieve resource pooling.,"[['CARDINAL', 1, 2]]"
155,S030881461301604X-1002.txt,"Two stock solutions of each standard compound were made; for AB, As(III), DMA and MMA the concentrations were 100 mg/L and 1 mg/L and for As(V) the concentrations were 10 mg/L and 0.1 mg/","[['CARDINAL', 0, 1], ['ORG', 11, 12], ['NORP', 13, 14], ['ORG', 16, 17], ['ORG', 18, 19], ['CARDINAL', 22, 23], ['CARDINAL', 38, 39], ['CARDINAL', 43, 44]]"
156,S030881461301604X-1002.txt,"The stock solutions were prepared in nitric acid (1%), with the exception of As(III), in which concentrated hydrochloric acid was used to promote its dissolution.","[['PERCENT', 56, 58]]"
157,S030881461301604X-1002.txt,"The final standard concentrations for all compounds were 1, 5, 10, 20 and 50 μg/L in 1% nitric acid.","[['CARDINAL', 87, 88], ['DATE', 89, 90], ['DATE', 91, 92], ['DATE', 93, 94], ['PERCENT', 100, 102]]"
158,S0019103513005058-3917.txt,"(2008), we apply a deposition velocity of 0.02 cm s−1 to all species, with two exceptions.","[['QUANTITY', 72, 74], ['CARDINAL', 80, 81]]"
159,S0019103513005058-3917.txt,"First, the deposition velocities for O2, H2, and CO are set to zero (following Zahnle et al., 2008).","[['ORDINAL', 83, 84], ['CARDINAL', 89, 90], ['CARDINAL', 98, 99], ['PERSON', 101, 102]]"
160,S0019103513005058-3917.txt,"Second, all species with a zero deposition velocity in Catling et al.","[['ORDINAL', 109, 110], ['CARDINAL', 115, 116]]"
161,S0019103513005058-3917.txt,(2010) are prescribed a zero deposition velocity because we consider them to be nonreactive.,"[['DATE', 124, 125], ['CARDINAL', 129, 130]]"
162,S0012821X12004384-1284.txt,C and N analyses (from which we present weight % C/N) were performed on 225 samples by combustion in a Costech ECS4010 Elemental Analyser (EA) calibrated against an acetanilide standard (Table S3).,"[['EVENT', 23, 26], ['CARDINAL', 30, 31], ['ORG', 36, 40], ['ORG', 41, 42], ['WORK_OF_ART', 49, 51]]"
163,S0012821X12004384-1284.txt,C/N atomic ratios were calculated by multiplying by 1.167.,"[['CARDINAL', 63, 64]]"
164,S0012821X12004384-1284.txt,"Carbon isotope analysis was carried out on 289 bulk rock samples (Table S4) after removing migrated hydrocarbons (Stephenson et al., 2005).","[['CARDINAL', 85, 86], ['PERSON', 98, 99], ['DATE', 103, 104]]"
165,S0012821X12004384-1284.txt,"The samples were refluxed for 24 h in an azeotropic mixture of dichloromethane and methanol (93:7, v/v).","[['CARDINAL', 141, 142], ['CARDINAL', 152, 153]]"
166,S0012821X12004384-1284.txt,Any calcites (shelly fragments) were removed by placing the samples in 5% HCl overnight before rinsing and drying down.,"[['PERCENT', 212, 214], ['TIME', 215, 216]]"
167,S0012821X12004384-1284.txt,Carbon isotope analysis was also carried out on palynology residues of the >250 μm size fractions dominated by AOM.,"[['ORG', 241, 242]]"
168,S0012821X12004384-1284.txt,"13C/12C analyses were performed on 35 samples by combustion in a Costech Elemental Analyser (EA) online to a VG TripleTrap and Optima dual-inlet mass spectrometer, with δ13C values calculated to the VPDB scale using a within-run laboratory standards calibrated against NBS-18, NBS-19, and NBS-22.","[['CARDINAL', 243, 244], ['CARDINAL', 248, 249], ['ORG', 254, 257], ['ORG', 258, 259], ['PERSON', 266, 267]]"
169,S0012821X12004384-1284.txt,"Replicate 13C/12C analyses were carried out on the section, and the mean standard deviation on the replicate analyses is 0.4‰.","[['CARDINAL', 298, 299], ['CARDINAL', 317, 318]]"
170,S0168945213001805-5014.txt,"The individual crystalline δ-endotoxins produced by Bt strains are poisonous to specific orders of Insecta (lepidopterans, dipterans, coleopterans, hymenopterans) and nematodes [163].","[['PERSON', 46, 47], ['CARDINAL', 59, 60]]"
171,S0032063312003054-2467.txt,"Even after discounting upward net flux of electrons from those signatures with isotropic electron energy distribution, category-4 still make up the second largest group and when added together with category-2 occur on 10% of MEX orbits.","[['ORDINAL', 112, 113], ['PERCENT', 123, 125], ['ORG', 126, 127]]"
172,S0960148113004989-3203.txt,"Therefore, the tidal period was defined to be P ≡ 10 min, which resulted in a tidal range of ±12 m. The simulation time was set to one full tidal period with a time step of Δt =","[['CARDINAL', 84, 85]]"
173,S0960148113004989-3203.txt,12 s.,"[['CARDINAL', 113, 114]]"
174,S0006322312001096-1194.txt,Age- and sex-adjusted odds ratio for 10% increment in risk was 2.84 (95% confidence interval [CI] 1.66–4.88) for the stroke risk score-incident stroke association and 2.25 (95% CI 1.92–2.65) for the CHD risk score-incident CHD association.,"[['PERCENT', 39, 41], ['CARDINAL', 45, 46], ['PERCENT', 47, 49], ['CARDINAL', 66, 67], ['PERCENT', 68, 70], ['CARDINAL', 71, 72], ['ORG', 75, 76], ['ORG', 80, 81]]"
175,S0006322312001096-1194.txt,"The corresponding odds ratios for the associations of CVD risk score with stroke and CHD were 1.34 (95% CI 1.11–1.62) and 2.14 (95% CI 1.85–2.48), respectively.","[['ORG', 91, 92], ['ORG', 97, 98], ['CARDINAL', 99, 100], ['PERCENT', 101, 103], ['CARDINAL', 107, 108], ['PERCENT', 109, 111], ['CARDINAL', 112, 113]]"
176,S0038071712001010-918.txt,AM fungal inoculum as a single factor was significant (P < 0.001) with distinct species combinations resulting in different levels of root colonisation.,[]
177,S0038071712001010-918.txt,"The individual inocula resulted in similar levels of colonisation (9.9%–16.2%; LSD = 7.01) irrespective of species, therefore valid comparisons with and between the mixed species could be made.","[['PERCENT', 36, 38], ['CARDINAL', 41, 42]]"
178,S0038071712001010-918.txt,"The highest percentage colonisation was observed in the two-species mixture of G. geosporum plus G. mosseae (25.4%), followed by the combination of all three species (23.8%).","[['CARDINAL', 68, 69], ['ORG', 73, 74], ['PERCENT', 79, 81], ['CARDINAL', 89, 90], ['PERCENT', 92, 94]]"
179,S0038071712001010-918.txt,"Percentage colonisation by G. geosporum plus G. mosseae in combination appeared to be additive relative to that observed by the species individually (16.2%, G. geosporum; 9.9% G. mosseae).","[['ORG', 99, 100], ['PERCENT', 119, 121], ['PERSON', 122, 123], ['PERCENT', 125, 127]]"
180,S0038071712001010-918.txt,"Colonisation was markedly reduced when G. mosseae and G. intraradices were paired (7.5%), particularly compared to the performance of G. intraradices individually (14.2%).","[['PERCENT', 144, 146], ['ORG', 154, 155], ['PERCENT', 158, 160]]"
181,S0032386113009889-2123.txt,The method used has been fully described elsewhere [49] and essentially it proposes that the criterion for debonding is based upon the energy released by the debonding process.,"[['CARDINAL', 23, 24]]"
182,S0032386113009889-2123.txt,"Namely, as implied above, the debonding of the silica nanoparticles from the epoxy matrix polymer appears to take place during the elastic deformation region and, as shown in Table 1, the yield stress for all modified epoxy polymers is approximately equal, irrespective of particle size.","[['LAW', 141, 143]]"
183,S0032386113009889-2123.txt,"It has therefore been assumed that the debonding takes place at an applied uniaxial stress of about 70 MPa, which equates to a hydrostatic stress at the crack tip of about 210 MPa.","[['CARDINAL', 177, 179], ['CARDINAL', 192, 194]]"
184,S0032386113009889-2123.txt,"Thus, the finite-element analysis simulations were analysed for an applied hydrostatic stress of 210 MPa.","[['CARDINAL', 212, 213]]"
185,S175058361300203X-1638.txt,"We studied two cases, one where the injection was performed at 34 °C and the other at 38 °C.","[['CARDINAL', 29, 30], ['CARDINAL', 39, 40], ['CARDINAL', 46, 47]]"
186,S175058361300203X-1638.txt,Results from the multiphase fluid flow simulations show that the difference between the two cases is small for the CO2 migration.,"[['CARDINAL', 63, 64]]"
187,S175058361300203X-1638.txt,"The difference in CO2 density between 34 °C and 38 °C decreases with decreasing pressure and, therefore, with increasing distance from the injection well.","[['DATE', 108, 109]]"
188,S175058361300203X-1638.txt,"Therefore, the modeled time-lapse seismic differences for the two temperature scenarios is minor regarding the qualitative analysis of the 4D seismic data from the Ketzin CO2 storage site (Fig.","[['CARDINAL', 138, 139], ['CARDINAL', 149, 150], ['PERSON', 159, 160]]"
189,S0167880913001229-1021.txt,•SOC stocks decreased by 12.4% in Costa Rica and 0.13% in Nicaragua after establishment of coffee AFS.•SOC stocks increased in the top 10 cm of soil; greater reduction occurred at 20–40 cm.•Organic management caused a greater increase in 0–10 cm SOC but did not influence reduction at depth.•Shade type effects on SOC were smaller; no significant difference between shaded and unshaded coffee.•SOC stocks tend to converge on a level determined by site environment during establishment.,"[['PERSON', 0, 1], ['PERCENT', 4, 6], ['GPE', 7, 9], ['PERCENT', 10, 12], ['GPE', 13, 14], ['ORG', 18, 19], ['QUANTITY', 24, 26], ['CARDINAL', 33, 34], ['QUANTITY', 41, 43], ['ORG', 43, 44]]"
190,S1387700313001822-661.txt,"To deliberate the chirality of the supramolecular architecture, solid state circular dichroism spectra were measured in a KCl matrix for GMP ligand and the single-crystals of complex 1 (Fig. 3(b)).","[['ORG', 21, 22], ['ORG', 32, 33], ['CARDINAL', 34, 35]]"
191,S1387700313001822-661.txt,"In solid-state, mutarotation is more difficult and the negative band at the 260 nm nearby can be detected which indicates that the GMP ligand is mainly β-anomers.","[['CARDINAL', 88, 89], ['ORG', 98, 99]]"
192,S1387700313001822-661.txt,"In the spectrum of complex 1, the weak negative band at 215–225 nm indicates that the GMP exists as l-ribo [5], which is induced by the strong π–π and hydrogen bonding interaction.","[['CARDINAL', 111, 112], ['CARDINAL', 118, 119]]"
193,S1387700313001822-661.txt,"For solid samples, CD spectroscopy is highly sensitive to even a very small distortion from planarity of the aromatic chromophore [12].","[['CARDINAL', 169, 170]]"
194,S1387700313001822-661.txt,"The strong negative CE centered at 297 nm (θ ≈ − 10 mdeg) is due to the excitation coupling of π → π* transitions of the aromatic chromophores, including the intra- and intermolecular coupling of the guanine chromophores [13], which is consistent with the single crystal structure.","[['ORG', 175, 176], ['CARDINAL', 178, 179], ['CARDINAL', 215, 216]]"
195,S2213671113001306-885.txt,"Claudin 19, ezrin, ZO1, and MCT1 are preferentially located on the apical side.","[['CARDINAL', 31, 32], ['PERSON', 35, 36]]"
196,S2213671113001306-885.txt,The scale bars represent 10 μm.,"[['CARDINAL', 57, 58]]"
197,S0925443913003037-1397.txt,We observed an approximately 54% reduction in the level of mt-tRNAPhe when compared with normal controls (Fig. 3D).,"[['PERCENT', 68, 70], ['PERSON', 84, 85], ['ORG', 86, 87]]"
198,S0167610513002729-1062.txt,"At x=0.64 H (about two-third of the way into the street, Fig.","[['CARDINAL', 4, 8], ['PERSON', 15, 16]]"
199,S0019103512004009-3976.txt,"As ηnet ranges from 0.1 to 1 (with the average solar flux), the velocity at the upper boundary increases from 2.6 km s−1 to 25 km s−1.","[['CARDINAL', 19, 20], ['QUANTITY', 38, 40], ['QUANTITY', 42, 44]]"
200,S0019103512004009-3976.txt,"However, the velocity does not increase linearly with stellar flux or without a bound – in the 100× case the velocity at the upper boundary is only 30 km s−1.","[['CARDINAL', 64, 65]]"
201,S0019103512004009-3976.txt,With ηnet = 0.1 the isothermal sonic point is located above the upper boundary whereas with ηnet = 1 it is located at 4Rp.,"[['CARDINAL', 106, 107], ['CARDINAL', 121, 122], ['CARDINAL', 126, 127]]"
202,S0019103512004009-3976.txt,This behavior is related to the temperature gradient and it is discussed further in Section 3.1.3.,"[['EVENT', 142, 144]]"
203,S0022459611006116-1448.txt,SQUID magnetometry measurements revealed that both samples 1 and 2 exhibit weak temperature independent paramagnetic behaviour (typically χM∼5×10−4 emu mol−1) between 5 and 300 K.,"[['CARDINAL', 7, 8], ['CARDINAL', 9, 10]]"
204,S0022459611006116-1448.txt,"[15,16].",[]
205,S0022459611006116-1448.txt,(A plot of χM vs. T for 1 and 2 is available as Supplementary information.),"[['ORG', 74, 75], ['CARDINAL', 78, 79], ['PERSON', 84, 85]]"
206,S0378383911001669-2260.txt,The magnitudes of the friction factors for the two beaches are very similar over the majority of the swash cycle.,"[['CARDINAL', 8, 9]]"
207,S0378383911001669-2260.txt,"(For reference, friction factors calculated assuming steady and uniform flow and evaluated from the measured depths and velocities, with equivalent roughness of 1.3 mm and 8.4 mm, are consistently higher for the rougher beach by approximately 50%.)","[['QUANTITY', 63, 65], ['QUANTITY', 66, 68], ['PERCENT', 77, 80]]"
208,S0378383911001669-2260.txt,"At x = 0.072 m the boundary layer has developed to only a limited extent, so the friction factors for the two beaches are very close.","[['CARDINAL', 149, 150], ['CARDINAL', 168, 169]]"
209,S0378383911001669-2260.txt,"Further up the slope, beyond x = 2.377 m, the friction factors are higher for the coarser 8.4 mm beach.","[['CARDINAL', 182, 183], ['QUANTITY', 193, 195]]"
210,S0378383911001669-2260.txt,"Somewhat later, cf values for the 8.4 mm beach catch up on the values for the 1.3 mm beach and then become higher than the 1.3 mm beach values, but only for locations higher up the beach.","[['QUANTITY', 280, 282], ['QUANTITY', 299, 301]]"
211,S0378383911001669-2260.txt,At the two lowest locations on the beach cf values are surprisingly similar during the backwash.,"[['CARDINAL', 315, 316]]"
212,S0032063312003054-2501.txt,"Out of the total 689 events of electron precipitation signatures, 85 were observed with a concurrent acceleration of heavy-ions.","[['CARDINAL', 4, 5], ['CARDINAL', 11, 12]]"
213,S0032063312003054-2501.txt,This accounts for 12% of precipitation signatures occurring on ∼5% of MEX orbits.,"[['PERCENT', 26, 28], ['ORG', 36, 37]]"
214,S0032063312003054-2501.txt,Only 37 events of electron precipitation signatures were observed with a peripheral acceleration of heavy-ions.,"[['CARDINAL', 39, 41]]"
215,S0032063312003054-2501.txt,This makes the peripheral acceleration of heavy-ions less common occurring on just 5% of precipitation signatures and on ∼2% of MEX orbits.,"[['PERCENT', 70, 73], ['PERCENT', 78, 80], ['ORG', 81, 82]]"
216,S0032386113005454-2308.txt,A tensile modulus of 3.19 ± 0.10 GPa was measured for the unmodified epoxy polymer.,"[['CARDINAL', 4, 5]]"
217,S0032386113005454-2308.txt,"The modulus decreased approximately linearly with increasing CSR content to 1.96 ± 0.08 GPa when 20 wt% of S-CSR particles were added, see Table 1.","[['ORG', 23, 24], ['CARDINAL', 26, 27], ['CARDINAL', 31, 32], ['LAW', 42, 44]]"
218,S0032386113005454-2308.txt,[30] using the same formulation of epoxy polymer but with different CSR particles.,"[['CARDINAL', 55, 56], ['ORG', 67, 68]]"
219,S0378383913001567-2462.txt,Power spectra of surface elevation for a JONSWAP spectrum with fp = 0.5 Hz and Hp = 1.8 cm: comparison of the numerical results (solid line) with experimental data (dashed line).,"[['ORG', 7, 8], ['CARDINAL', 12, 13], ['QUANTITY', 17, 19]]"
220,S0165587612003680-998.txt,"Differences between adults and children were explored on a per-patient (rather than per-ear) basis; where data existed for two ears, the per-patient analysis was carried out using the criteria of at least one ear being culture/confocal positive and at least one ear containing biofilms.","[['CARDINAL', 25, 26], ['CARDINAL', 40, 43], ['CARDINAL', 50, 53]]"
221,S0165587612003680-998.txt,"Children appeared to have a greater number of culture-positive, confocal-positive, and biofilm results than adults (54.3% vs. 14.3%, 82.9% vs. 57.1%, and 67.9% vs. 0%, respectively).","[['PERCENT', 79, 81], ['PERCENT', 82, 84], ['PERCENT', 85, 87], ['PERCENT', 88, 90], ['PERCENT', 92, 94], ['PERCENT', 95, 97]]"
222,S0165587612003680-998.txt,"However, only the presence of biofilms reached statistical significance (Fisher's exact test p = 0.02).","[['ORG', 112, 113], ['CARDINAL', 118, 119]]"
223,S027737911400050X-2401.txt,"For late Quaternary records, most tephra horizons in sediment cores are dated by (linear) interpolation of 14C dates of carbonates, bulk sediment or organic remains.","[['PERSON', 2, 3]]"
224,S027737911400050X-2401.txt,"Both phenomena can result in anomalous 14C ages and an offset from the real age of the dated material, which is not necessarily constant through time in the sediment section (Geyh et al., 1998;","[['DATE', 103, 104]]"
225,S027737911400050X-2401.txt,"Yu et al., 2007).","[['DATE', 110, 111]]"
226,S027737911400050X-2401.txt,"This offset from the real age can be of the order of several hundred or even more than a thousand years if bulk sediment or carbonates are dated, and can thus lead to misleading or erroneous age models if it is not taken into account (Geyh et al., 1998; Bertrand et al., 2012).","[['CARDINAL', 125, 127], ['DATE', 129, 134], ['DATE', 165, 166], ['GPE', 167, 168], ['DATE', 172, 173]]"
227,S027737911400050X-2401.txt,"Appropriate tephra characterisation can potentially also help in evaluating the reservoir effect in a sediment section by providing a tie-point in the age model, provided the age of the tephra is well known from one or more independent sources (e.g., 14C dating on charcoal incorporated in terrestrial deposits, for example the well-constrained 3.00–3.05 ka cal BP Alpehué Pumice (So-A) eruption from Sollipulli; Supplementary Table 1; Naranjo et al., 1993b).","[['CARDINAL', 238, 239], ['CARDINAL', 261, 262], ['WORK_OF_ART', 276, 279]]"
228,S2213671113000908-810.txt,"Our group has developed a defined culture system to direct the differentiation of hPSCs into a near-homogenous population of definitive endoderm (DE) cells that have the capacity to differentiate into hepatocytes and pancreatic progenitors (Brown et al., 2011; Cho et al., 2012; Rashid et al., 2010; Touboul et al., 2010; Vallier et al., 2009a; Yusa et al., 2011).","[['ORG', 24, 25], ['PERSON', 39, 40], ['DATE', 44, 45], ['PERSON', 46, 47], ['DATE', 51, 52], ['DATE', 58, 59], ['GPE', 60, 61], ['DATE', 65, 66], ['PERSON', 67, 68], ['DATE', 72, 73], ['PERSON', 74, 75], ['DATE', 79, 80]]"
229,S2213671113000908-810.txt,Flow cytometry analyses showed that 80% of the resulting DE population coexpresses CXCR4 and SOX17 (Figure S1D).,"[['PERCENT', 142, 144], ['ORG', 147, 148], ['ORG', 150, 151]]"
230,S175058361300203X-1556.txt,"8) of both the 34 °C and 38 °C options look very similar and also show some similarity to the real data, also shown in Fig.","[['CARDINAL', 8, 9], ['DATE', 16, 17], ['PERSON', 36, 37]]"
231,S175058361300203X-1556.txt,8.,"[['CARDINAL', 38, 39]]"
232,S175058361300203X-1556.txt,(2012).,"[['DATE', 82, 83]]"
233,S175058361300203X-1556.txt,Seismic amplitude differences between the 38 °C and 34 °C scenarios correspond to less than 1% of the amplitude values of the baseline (Fig.,"[['CARDINAL', 125, 126], ['PERCENT', 131, 135], ['PERSON', 143, 144]]"
234,S175058361300203X-1556.txt,8).,"[['CARDINAL', 145, 146]]"
235,S175058361300203X-1556.txt,"Since the normalized root mean square (NRMS) differences in the 3D time-lapse data are greater than 10% (Kashubin et al., 2011) these temperature effects in the reservoir will not be resolvable with surface seismic methods at the Ketzin site.","[['ORG', 159, 160], ['PERCENT', 165, 169], ['PERSON', 170, 171], ['DATE', 175, 176], ['ORG', 193, 194]]"
236,S0960148113005727-1181.txt,"Operating efficiency: sub-optimal control systems, misaligned components and electrical losses within the farm are found to reduce output by 2% in well-performing field installations relative to the turbine's supplied power curve [30];","[['PERCENT', 23, 25], ['CARDINAL', 40, 41]]"
237,S1873506113001116-1204.txt,"BC1 cells cultured on E8 feeder-free conditions (E8-Matrigel or E8-VNT-N) for at least 3 passages were seeded as a single cell suspension in E8 medium supplemented with Y27632 on the first day (Watanabe et al., 2007).","[['CARDINAL', 52, 53], ['PRODUCT', 58, 61], ['ORG', 62, 67], ['CARDINAL', 69, 72], ['CARDINAL', 81, 82], ['GPE', 85, 86], ['DATE', 87, 90], ['DATE', 96, 97]]"
238,S1873506113001116-1204.txt,The cells survived and formed convex dish-shaped aggregates within 24 h due to the gravity force (Fig. 1a).,"[['CARDINAL', 110, 111], ['PERSON', 118, 119], ['CARDINAL', 120, 121]]"
239,S1873506113001116-1204.txt,"BC1 cells expanded in static suspension in E8 medium with an average rate of 3.7 ± 0.9 fold per passage, 3.7 × 106 fold increase in total with > 99% of the cells being TRA-1–60+ after 13 passages (Fig.","[['CARDINAL', 148, 149], ['CARDINAL', 155, 156], ['QUANTITY', 157, 159], ['CARDINAL', 162, 163], ['PERCENT', 170, 173], ['CARDINAL', 180, 181], ['ORG', 183, 184]]"
240,S1873506113001116-1204.txt,"1b,c).","[['CARDINAL', 185, 186]]"
241,S1873506113001116-1204.txt,"We also examined the differentiation potential of expanded cells, using the spin-EB method (Ng et al., 2008, 2005;","[['DATE', 214, 215]]"
242,S1873506113001116-1204.txt,"Yu et al., 2008).",[]
243,S1873506113001116-1204.txt,"We found that under the hematopoiesis-inducing condition, leukocyte-like cells emerged around day 10 (Fig. 1d) with 46.8% ± 1.6% of the cells becoming CD34+CD45+ HPCs (Fig. 1e).","[['DATE', 239, 242], ['PERSON', 243, 244], ['CARDINAL', 245, 246], ['PERCENT', 248, 250], ['PERCENT', 250, 253], ['ORG', 261, 262], ['CARDINAL', 263, 264]]"
244,S1873506113001116-1204.txt,"These results indicate that undifferentiated hiPSCs can be expanded in suspension in E8 medium supplemented with one-day treatment of Y27632, and retain their differentiation potential.","[['CARDINAL', 278, 279], ['DATE', 282, 285], ['GPE', 287, 288]]"
245,S0019103512003995-1283.txt,Density profiles O and H based on the C2 model (Paper I) and the density profile of H based on the empirical model of K10 with a mean temperature of 7200 K.,"[['ORG', 26, 27], ['CARDINAL', 32, 33]]"
246,S0012821X12004384-1148.txt,"Located within proximity to the North Atlantic igneous province (NAIP), the Kilda Basin, and the northern rain belt (paleolatitude 54 °N) during the PETM, this is a critical region for testing proposed triggers of atmospheric carbon release that may have caused the global negative carbon isotope excursion (CIE) in marine and terrestrial environments.","[['LOC', 33, 36], ['ORG', 39, 40], ['LOC', 42, 45], ['DATE', 53, 54], ['ORG', 59, 60], ['ORG', 85, 86]]"
247,S0012821X12004384-1148.txt,"Multiproxy palynological, geochemical, and sedimentologic records demonstrate enhanced halocline stratification and terrigenous deposition well before (103 yrs) the CIE, interpreted as due to either tectonic uplift possibly from a nearby magmatic intrusion, or increased precipitation and fluvial runoff possibly from an enhanced hydrologic cycle.","[['PERSON', 138, 139], ['CARDINAL', 156, 157], ['ORG', 160, 161]]"
248,S0006322312001096-626.txt,Association Between Framingham Risk Scores (per 10% Increase) and Subsequent Onset of Depressive Symptoms Before and After Age 65,"[['PERSON', 2, 5], ['PERCENT', 7, 9], ['DATE', 20, 22]]"
249,S0960148113004989-3258.txt,3c.,"[['CARDINAL', 11, 12]]"
250,S0960148113004989-3258.txt,"For this test, inequality constraints were applied to enforce a minimum distance of 30 m between each turbine.","[['CARDINAL', 36, 37]]"
251,S0960148113004989-3258.txt,"The optimisation algorithm terminated after 56 iterations (55 gradient evaluations, 73 functional evaluations).","[['CARDINAL', 47, 48], ['CARDINAL', 50, 51], ['CARDINAL', 54, 55]]"
252,S0960148113004989-3258.txt,"The optimised farm layout extracts 40.6 MW, which corresponds to an increase of 31% compared to the initial layout (30.9 MW) (Fig. 8c).","[['CARDINAL', 64, 65], ['ORG', 65, 66], ['PERCENT', 73, 75], ['CARDINAL', 81, 82], ['ORG', 82, 83], ['PERSON', 85, 86], ['CARDINAL', 87, 88]]"
253,S2211124712002884-1060.txt,"The cells were maintained in Dulbecco's modified Eagle's medium supplemented with 10% fetal bovine serum, 1X nonessential amino acids, and penicillin/streptomycin (100 U/ml).","[['ORG', 108, 109], ['PERCENT', 113, 115], ['CARDINAL', 119, 120], ['CARDINAL', 129, 130]]"
254,S2211124712002884-1060.txt,"iPSCs were generated as described previously (Takahashi et al., 2007).","[['PERSON', 142, 143], ['DATE', 147, 148]]"
255,S016412121300188X-4392.txt,"A precision of 1.00 (US = UH) means the hash function is 100% accurate (i.e., it produces a unique hash value for every distinct slice) whereas a precision of 1/US means that the hash function produces the same hash value for every slice leaving UH = 1.","[['CARDINAL', 22, 23], ['GPE', 24, 25], ['PERCENT', 33, 35], ['MONEY', 54, 57], ['CARDINAL', 73, 74]]"
257,S016412121300188X-4640.txt,Indent  has one extremely large coherent cluster that spans 52.1% of the program's vertices.,"[['CARDINAL', 3, 4], ['PERCENT', 10, 12]]"
258,S016412121300188X-4640.txt,The cluster is formed of vertices from 54 functions spread over 7 source files.,"[['CARDINAL', 25, 26], ['CARDINAL', 29, 30]]"
259,S016412121300188X-4640.txt,"Out of the 54 functions, 26 begin with the common prefix of “handle_token”.","[['CARDINAL', 48, 49], ['CARDINAL', 51, 52]]"
260,S016412121300188X-4640.txt,These 26 functions are individually responsible for handling a specific token during the formatting process.,"[['CARDINAL', 63, 64]]"
261,S0960148113002048-3775.txt,"(29), is presented in Fig.","[['CARDINAL', 9, 10], ['PERSON', 15, 16]]"
262,S0960148113002048-3775.txt,13.,"[['CARDINAL', 17, 18]]"
263,S0960148113002048-3775.txt,"Strategies A–C lead to similar generator efficiencies, the two major trends being that increased average wind speed causes a higher generator efficiency while a higher frequency of the wind speed reduces the generator efficiency.","[['CARDINAL', 30, 31]]"
264,S0960148113002048-3775.txt,In the low wind speed case at wind frequencies of 0.01–0.03,"[['CARDINAL', 129, 130]]"
265,S0960148113002048-3775.txt,In the low wind speed case at wind frequencies above 0.003,"[['CARDINAL', 177, 178]]"
266,S0960148113002048-3775.txt,10 and 11.,[]
267,S0006322312001096-1177.txt,"The Whitehall II study is a prospective cohort study of British civil servants established in 1985 to study associations between risk factors, pathophysiological changes, and clinical disease (22).","[['NORP', 10, 11], ['DATE', 15, 16], ['CARDINAL', 30, 31]]"
268,S0006322312001096-1177.txt,"The target population was all London-based office staff, aged 35 to 55, working in 20 civil service departments on recruitment to the study in 1985 to 1988 (phase 1).","[['GPE', 38, 39], ['DATE', 45, 48], ['CARDINAL', 51, 52], ['DATE', 61, 64], ['CARDINAL', 66, 67]]"
269,S0006322312001096-1177.txt,"With a response of 73%, the cohort consisted of 10,308 employees (6895 men and 3413 women).","[['PERCENT', 73, 75], ['CARDINAL', 80, 81], ['CARDINAL', 83, 84]]"
271,S0006322312001096-1177.txt,"Phase 3 was the first time that all components of the Framingham risk algorithms were measured, making it the baseline for the analyses we report here.","[['CARDINAL', 159, 160], ['ORDINAL', 162, 163], ['GPE', 169, 170]]"
273,S0927024813001955-576.txt,Comparison of the performance of ITO/AALD ZnO/P3HT:PCBM/MoO3/Ag devices with the 125 nm thick AALD ZnO film post-annealed at different temperatures for 1 h.,"[['ORG', 0, 1], ['ORG', 5, 6], ['PERSON', 10, 11], ['CARDINAL', 20, 21], ['CARDINAL', 33, 34]]"
274,S0927024813001955-576.txt,The devices were measured after one week of storage in the dark under ambient conditions.,"[['DATE', 57, 59]]"
275,S2211124713006475-1195.txt,"To assess the in vivo properties of hESC-derived trigeminal placode precursors, PIP-induced neuronal clusters, derived from a constitutively GFP-positive hESC line (Figures S5A and S5B), were injected into the developing chick embryo targeting the early trigeminal anlage at H&H stage 10–12 (Figure S5C).","[['ORG', 24, 25], ['ORG', 49, 50], ['DATE', 51, 52]]"
276,S2211124713006475-1195.txt,"Two days after in ovo transplantation, surviving GFP+ cells were found dispersed in the area of the endogenous chick trigeminal ganglion (Figure 4P).","[['DATE', 78, 80], ['CARDINAL', 102, 103]]"
277,S2211124713006475-1195.txt,The in vivo fiber outgrowth 2 days after transplantation was reminiscent of the extensive in vitro fiber outgrowth of replated trigeminal neuron clusters (Figure S5A).,"[['DATE', 150, 152]]"
278,S175058361300203X-1483.txt,(2010) to account for the lateral variability in the petrophysical properties of the storage formation at Ketzin.,"[['DATE', 16, 17], ['ORG', 33, 34]]"
279,S175058361300203X-1483.txt,(2010) performed simulations on multiple realizations of the Ketzin reservoir using a stochastic Monte Carlo approach in order to take into account the high degree of uncertainty in the reservoir characterization at the scale required for fluid flow simulations.,"[['DATE', 40, 41], ['ORG', 49, 50], ['PERSON', 54, 56]]"
280,S175058361300203X-1483.txt,"Hydrogeological studies at the Ketzin site (Norden et al., 2010) have shown that a 2D radially symmetric model of the upper part (33 m) of the Stuttgart Formation can be used to interpret the 3D data acquired near the injection well (Fig. 7).","[['GPE', 121, 122], ['DATE', 129, 130], ['CARDINAL', 135, 136], ['CARDINAL', 144, 145], ['ORG', 148, 151], ['ORG', 157, 158], ['PERSON', 165, 166], ['CARDINAL', 167, 168]]"
281,S175058361300203X-1483.txt,"This model accounts for the presence of channel sandstones in the reservoir that are the most favorable for CO2 migration and contains effective porosities in the range of 20–25% (Förster et al., 2010).","[['PERCENT', 198, 200], ['DATE', 206, 207]]"
282,S175058361300203X-1483.txt,"As known from core and log analysis of the injection well Ktzi201/2007 and the first observation well Ktzi200/2007, the reservoir is composed of two high porosity sandstone layers.","[['GPE', 220, 221], ['ORDINAL', 223, 224], ['ORG', 226, 227], ['CARDINAL', 233, 234]]"
283,S175058361300203X-1483.txt,"These layers are separated by a thin strongly cemented sandstone layer (Norden et al., 2010).","[['DATE', 256, 257]]"
284,S175058361300203X-1483.txt,"However, this layer is known to be a significant constraint to fluid migration due to its low permeability (Wiese et al., 2010).","[['DATE', 313, 314]]"
285,S0378383911001669-1088.txt,Depth time-series and depth-averaged bed-parallel velocity time-series at x = 0.072 m for the 1.3 mm sand-rough beach; results from 50 individual events (grey) and ensemble-averaged result (black).,"[['CARDINAL', 18, 19], ['QUANTITY', 22, 24], ['CARDINAL', 31, 32]]"
286,S0012821X12004384-1640.txt,A negative carbon isotope excursion of 5‰ has been identified from δ13CTOC and δ13CAOM in an expanded Paleocene–Eocene boundary section from the central North Sea Basin.,"[['LOC', 25, 28]]"
287,S0012821X12004384-1640.txt,"Enhanced halocline stratification and terrigenous input from 4 m before the CIE may indicate tectonic uplift and oceanic restriction of the North Sea, supporting hypotheses for NAIP volcanism as a trigger for the CIE (Svensen et al., 2004), and/or increased terrigenous runoff and regional precipitation, supporting hypotheses of an enhanced hydrologic cycle triggering carbon release (Bice and Marotzke, 2002).","[['CARDINAL', 78, 79], ['ORG', 82, 83], ['LOC', 91, 94], ['ORG', 98, 99], ['ORG', 105, 106], ['DATE', 112, 113], ['ORG', 134, 135], ['DATE', 138, 139]]"
288,S0012821X12004384-1640.txt,"At this location (paleolatitude 54 oN) increased precipitation would support the hypothesis that a poleward migration of storm tracks from an enhanced hydrologic cycle resulted from global warming during the PETM (Pagani et al., 2006b).","[['DATE', 201, 202], ['DATE', 235, 236]]"
289,S0378383912000130-3732.txt,9 presents time-series of the hydraulic gradient at several cross-shore locations for the 1.5 mm and the 8.5 mm beaches.,"[['CARDINAL', 24, 25]]"
290,S0378383912000130-3732.txt,"Note that the results are given relative to time t0, which is the bore arrival time at each cross-shore location, and only while the wetting front is still moving towards the groundwater table.",[]
291,S0019103512001388-3081.txt,"The observed peak in the fractional integrated differential brightness of BS1 in the H filter was observed to be 0.64% in the discovery image on 26 October 2011, and declined to 0.02% by December 16.","[['PERCENT', 19, 21], ['DATE', 26, 29], ['PERCENT', 33, 35], ['DATE', 36, 38]]"
292,S0927775713009606-1216.txt,"Wide-angle diffraction patterns were acquired using a Bruker AXS D8 diffractometer with CuKα (λ = 1.5418 Å), over a 2θ range from 5° to 85°, using a step size of 0.1° and a counting time per step of 4 s. CdS particle size was calculated using the Scherrer equation, assuming a spherical particle morphology and using a Gaussian peak fitting procedure to determine the FWHM (i.e. K = 0.9).","[['ORG', 9, 10], ['PERSON', 14, 15], ['CARDINAL', 18, 19], ['CARDINAL', 24, 25], ['CARDINAL', 27, 28], ['CARDINAL', 30, 31], ['CARDINAL', 38, 39], ['CARDINAL', 47, 48], ['ORG', 56, 57], ['PERSON', 67, 68], ['ORG', 74, 75], ['CARDINAL', 79, 80]]"
293,S1873506113001116-710.txt,(a) Light microscope image of aggregates after 48 h post-inoculation of single suspension BC1 cells in ultra-low attachment plates.,"[['CARDINAL', 20, 21]]"
294,S1873506113001116-710.txt,"(b) BC1 cells cultured in E8 medium, expanded in static suspension culture for 13 passages (45 days, n = 3).","[['CARDINAL', 44, 45], ['CARDINAL', 53, 54], ['DATE', 56, 58], ['CARDINAL', 61, 62]]"
295,S1873506113001116-710.txt,(c) Flow cytometry plots (n = 3) of TRA-1–60 expression in hiPSCs after 13 passages in static suspension.,"[['CARDINAL', 73, 74], ['NORP', 76, 77], ['DATE', 79, 80], ['CARDINAL', 81, 82]]"
296,S1873506113001116-710.txt,(d) Light microscope image of HPC-like single suspending cells emerging around a spin-EB on day 14.,"[['DATE', 107, 109]]"
297,S1873506113001116-710.txt,(e) Flow cytometry plots (n = 2) of CD34 and CD45 expression in day-14 spin EBs.,"[['CARDINAL', 119, 120], ['PRODUCT', 122, 123], ['PRODUCT', 124, 125]]"
298,S1873506113001116-710.txt,Scale bars = 200 μm.,"[['CARDINAL', 139, 140]]"
299,S1084804513001987-7409.txt,"In this section, we propose a strategy to further reduce the distortion area, which is called two-dimensional scaling.","[['CARDINAL', 18, 19]]"
300,S1084804513001987-7409.txt,"Two-dimensional scaling works with any quantization method, such as uniform scaling or logarithmic scaling.","[['CARDINAL', 23, 24]]"
301,S1084804513001987-7409.txt,We then calculate the upper bound of the distortion area produced by two-dimensional scaling.,"[['CARDINAL', 53, 54]]"
302,S1084804513001987-7409.txt,"Finally, we consider both quantization schemes, namely, uniform scaling and logarithmic scaling, and compare the error of two-dimensional scaling with that of the existing quantization-based algorithms.","[['CARDINAL', 79, 80]]"
303,S0960896612001022-1223.txt,KSS is a multisystem disorder defined clinically by the triad of PEO and pigmentary retinopathy with onset before the age of 20 years plus at least one of: cardiac conduction block; cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) protein concentration greater than 0.1 g/L; cerebellar ataxia [76–80].,"[['ORG', 0, 1], ['DATE', 18, 23], ['CARDINAL', 24, 27], ['ORG', 36, 37], ['CARDINAL', 42, 43], ['CARDINAL', 50, 51]]"
304,S0960896612001022-1223.txt,"The most common magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) findings are cerebral and cerebellar atrophy with bilateral, often symmetrical, hyperintense lesions in the subcortical white matter, thalamus, basal ganglia and brainstem [81–83].",[]
305,S0960896612001022-1223.txt,"Interestingly, there appears to be little correlation between neurological deficits and the severity of the MRI features [84].","[['CARDINAL', 152, 153]]"
306,S0960896612001022-1223.txt,KSS is most commonly associated with single large-scale deletions of mtDNA [56].,"[['ORG', 155, 156], ['CARDINAL', 169, 170]]"
307,S0960896612001022-1223.txt,We recently identified a case of KSS caused by nuclear genomic dysfunction due to mutations in RRM2B in a patient with multiple deletions of the mtDNA [85].,"[['ORG', 178, 179], ['CARDINAL', 199, 200]]"
308,S0167610513002729-1127.txt,The situation for the 45° case is more interesting (Fig. 9).,"[['CARDINAL', 4, 5], ['PERSON', 11, 12], ['CARDINAL', 13, 14]]"
309,S175058361300203X-1542.txt,"It is well known that the seismic velocity in sandstones saturated with brine does not depend on temperatures in the range of 34–38 °C (e.g. Mavko, 2005).","[['CARDINAL', 22, 23], ['GPE', 27, 28], ['DATE', 29, 30]]"
310,S175058361300203X-1542.txt,"To demonstrate this we calculated the difference in Vp between both temperature scenarios present at the Ketzin site at the time of the 1st 3D seismic repeat campaign (Ivanova et al., 2012) using Gassmann's equations (1951) for 50% CO2 saturation.","[['ORG', 48, 49], ['MONEY', 56, 57], ['ORG', 61, 62], ['DATE', 66, 67], ['ORG', 69, 70], ['DATE', 73, 74], ['PERCENT', 76, 78]]"
311,S175058361300203X-1542.txt,The resulting difference between the scenarios in Vp is less than 5 m,[]
312,S175058361300203X-1542.txt,"Considering the uncertainties (e.g. ±5% error in CO2 saturation) in the petrophysical experiments (Kummerow and Spangenberg, 2011; Ivanova et al., 2012) corresponding to ±70 m/s in Vp (Fig. 5), we did not take into account the Vp changes (Fig. 5, Eq.","[['PERSON', 113, 114], ['GPE', 115, 116], ['DATE', 117, 118], ['ORG', 119, 120], ['DATE', 124, 125], ['PERSON', 135, 136], ['CARDINAL', 137, 138], ['ORG', 150, 151], ['CARDINAL', 152, 153], ['PERSON', 154, 155]]"
313,S175058361300203X-1542.txt,(1)) due to the different temperature scenarios (34 and 38 °C).,"[['CARDINAL', 167, 168]]"
314,S0925443913001385-1429.txt,"(Dulbecco's modified Eagle's medium, Gibco) supplemented with 10% (v/v) fetal calf serum (FCS), 2 mM l-glutamine, 50 μg/ml uridine, 110 μg/ml pyruvate, 10,000 U/ml penicillin G and 10,000 μg/ml streptomycin.","[['ORG', 12, 13], ['PERCENT', 20, 22], ['CARDINAL', 40, 41], ['CARDINAL', 46, 47], ['CARDINAL', 52, 53], ['CARDINAL', 59, 60]]"
315,S0927024813002961-1334.txt,"In the short term, there is the direct influence of the environment as discussed in Section 4.","[['LAW', 30, 32]]"
316,S0927024813002961-1334.txt,"In the mid-term there is the Staebler–Wronski effect for a-Si [48,49] or pre-conditioning for CIGS, which affects the annual energy prediction by less than 5% typically and are not further explored here.","[['ORG', 41, 42], ['PERSON', 43, 44], ['ORG', 57, 58], ['DATE', 62, 63], ['PERCENT', 66, 70]]"
317,S0927024813002961-1334.txt,"The effect for CIGS is slightly contradictory as there is no clarity of the time scales involved yet [4,50].","[['ORG', 81, 82]]"
318,S0927024813002961-1334.txt,There are also long-term gradual degradation effects which affect all device technologies [51].,"[['CARDINAL', 115, 116]]"
319,S0927024813002961-1334.txt,The maximum power point data of all devices within an irradiance range of 650–750 W/m2 have been extracted and corrected to 700 W/m2 and 25 °C using bi-linear interpolation.,"[['CARDINAL', 156, 157], ['ORG', 157, 160], ['CARDINAL', 166, 167], ['ORG', 167, 170]]"
320,S0927024813002961-1334.txt,9 (top graph).,"[['CARDINAL', 226, 227]]"
321,S0927024813002961-1334.txt,"To contrast power and energy, the monthly performance ratios are also plotted (bottom graph)Table 2.","[['DATE', 239, 240], ['CARDINAL', 248, 249]]"
322,S0167577X13006393-644.txt,Sintering of pure HA particles is usually reported to occur above 1000 °C.,"[['CARDINAL', 10, 12]]"
323,S0167577X13006393-644.txt,Most investigators agree that pure HA (ratio CaP=1.67) is stable in an air and argon atmosphere at temperatures upto 1200 °C,[]
324,S0167577X13006393-644.txt,[18–20].,"[['CARDINAL', 61, 62]]"
325,S0167577X13006393-644.txt,"However, decomposition of HA at temperatures as low as 800 °C has been observed for calcium deficient HA samples [19].","[['CARDINAL', 86, 87]]"
326,S0925443913001385-839.txt,De novo synthesis of mitochondrial proteins was determined in patient (P) and control (C) fibroblasts under conditions that inhibited cytosolic translation [45].,"[['CARDINAL', 30, 31]]"
327,S0925443913001385-839.txt,"In vivo incorporation of 35S-methionine/cysteine into mitochondrially encoded proteins was visualised by separation of cell lysate (50 μg) through SDS–PAGE, exposure of the dried gel to a PhosphorImage screen, followed by Storm and ImageQuant analysis (upper panel).","[['QUANTITY', 37, 40], ['CARDINAL', 54, 55], ['ORG', 69, 70], ['ORG', 74, 75], ['ORG', 76, 77]]"
328,S1367912013002277-1213.txt,The collected particles include 2.5–10 μm (PM10) and less than 2.5 μm (PM2.5).,"[['CARDINAL', 50, 53]]"
329,S0016236113008041-2924.txt,"Sensitivity analysis carried out on MTDATA software, for 9 and 21 trace elements.","[['ORG', 5, 6], ['CARDINAL', 9, 10], ['CARDINAL', 11, 12]]"
330,S030881461301604X-1001.txt,"The water was ultrapure water obtained from a Milli-Q-system (Millipore Corporation, Bedford, MA, USA) and nitric acid (68 – 70%), hydrochloric acid (30%), ammonium carbonate (powder), hydrogen peroxide (30%) and formic acid (98%) were all from J. T. Baker (Deventer, Netherlands).","[['ORG', 14, 16], ['ORG', 17, 18], ['GPE', 19, 20], ['GPE', 21, 22], ['PERCENT', 27, 31], ['PERCENT', 36, 38], ['PERCENT', 49, 51], ['PERCENT', 56, 58], ['PERSON', 62, 65], ['GPE', 66, 67], ['GPE', 68, 69]]"
331,S0921818113002245-1571.txt,Three different methods were used to recover sediment cores in 2010.,"[['CARDINAL', 0, 1], ['DATE', 10, 11]]"
332,S0921818113002245-1571.txt,"The upper 0.8 m of sediments were recovered using a freeze-coring technique (Renberg and Hansson, 1993).","[['CARDINAL', 14, 15], ['PERSON', 27, 28], ['PERSON', 29, 30], ['DATE', 31, 32]]"
333,S0921818113002245-1571.txt,This core recovers a thin (approximately 1 cm) vertical slab of relatively undisturbed sediment and was only used for correlation purposes.,"[['QUANTITY', 41, 43]]"
334,S0921818113002245-1571.txt,Five cores for paleomagnetic measurements were recovered using a rod-operated fixed-piston corer described by Snowball and Sandgren (2002).,"[['CARDINAL', 81, 82], ['PERSON', 99, 100], ['DATE', 103, 104]]"
335,S0921818113002245-1571.txt,"This system recovers complete 4.8 m long cores of sediment in PVC tubes of either 60 or 63 mm internal diameter, although it is not oriented to a geographic azimuth for practical reasons.","[['CARDINAL', 110, 111], ['ORG', 117, 118], ['CARDINAL', 121, 122]]"
336,S0921818113002245-1571.txt,"This system provided four overlapping cores for paleomagnetic reconstructions to a sediment depth of 8 m (GD0a, GP1, GP2 and GP4.","[['CARDINAL', 144, 145], ['CARDINAL', 155, 156]]"
337,S0921818113002245-1571.txt,A cable operated Uwitec “Niederreiter” percussion piston corer (three metre long drives) was subsequently used to recover sediments to depth of approximately 11.8 m (drives GD1–GD4).,"[['PERSON', 178, 179], ['QUANTITY', 186, 188], ['MONEY', 200, 203], ['PRODUCT', 205, 208]]"
338,S0921818113002245-1571.txt,"Sandy sediment was recovered in the bottom of GD4, equivalent to a sediment depth between 11.8 m and 11.5 m and it proved impossible to penetrate through this material with the available equipment.","[['CARDINAL', 226, 227], ['CARDINAL', 229, 230]]"
339,S0019103513005058-4098.txt,"The shape of the profile is preserved, but the surface temperature is increased from 211 K to 284 K (a temperature increase of ∼35%), with the latter temperature being more representative of surface temperatures on Earth.","[['CARDINAL', 70, 72], ['LOC', 95, 96]]"
340,S1873506114000075-1242.txt,3A.,[]
341,S1873506114000075-1242.txt,"To test whether FAP-specific iPS cells can differentiate into hepatocyte-like cells, we analyzed several markers via real-time PCR analysis on Day 5 (D5), D13 and D20 differentiated FAP-specific iPS cells (Fig. 3B).","[['ORG', 25, 26], ['DATE', 49, 51], ['CARDINAL', 52, 53], ['ORG', 57, 58], ['ORG', 59, 60], ['PERSON', 65, 66]]"
342,S1873506114000075-1242.txt,Quantitative imaging analysis revealed that approximately 78 ± 0.6% of cells were Sox17-positive on D5 and approximately 88 ± 1.1% of cells were AFP-positive on D13 and approximately 29 ± 0.9% of cells were ALB-positive on D20 (Fig. 3D).,"[['PERCENT', 179, 181], ['CARDINAL', 188, 189], ['PERCENT', 192, 195], ['ORG', 198, 199], ['PERCENT', 207, 209], ['ORG', 212, 213], ['ORG', 216, 217], ['PERSON', 218, 219], ['ORG', 220, 221]]"
343,S1873506114000075-1242.txt,The ALB secretion in the media of differentiated FAP-specific iPS cells on D20 was approximately 20 μg/ml (Fig. 3E).,"[['ORG', 224, 225], ['ORG', 231, 232], ['ORG', 237, 238], ['CARDINAL', 240, 241], ['PERSON', 245, 246]]"
344,S2213671113000738-430.txt,(I–M) Teratoma formation at 3 months after transplantation in the testes of SCID mice.,"[['PERSON', 5, 6], ['DATE', 8, 10]]"
345,S016412121300188X-4069.txt,"As an example, the open source calculator bc contains 9438 lines of code represented by 7538 SDG vertices.","[['CARDINAL', 10, 11], ['CARDINAL', 16, 17], ['ORG', 17, 18]]"
346,S016412121300188X-4069.txt,"3a, contains a large plateau that spans almost 70% of the MSG.","[['CARDINAL', 31, 32], ['PERCENT', 39, 42], ['ORG', 44, 45]]"
347,S0960148113004989-3327.txt,The averaged power extracted during one cycle increased by 22% from 48.4 MW to 59.0 MW (Fig. 10e).,"[['CARDINAL', 5, 6], ['PERCENT', 9, 11], ['CARDINAL', 12, 13], ['ORG', 13, 14], ['CARDINAL', 15, 16], ['ORG', 16, 17], ['ORG', 18, 19], ['DATE', 20, 21]]"
348,S0960148113004989-3327.txt,"Since the computational domain is symmetric and the simulation time covered one full period, the optimised layout is expected to be symmetric in the x-direction.",[]
349,S0960148113004989-3327.txt,The turbine alignment consists of two distorted ∨ shapes whose open ends face the in/-outflow boundaries.,"[['CARDINAL', 74, 75]]"
350,S0167610512002292-3305.txt,"The results from three different simulations are presented here—one with a 1.0 kg plate, a second with a 6.35 kg plate (typical of a clay roofing tile), and a third with a 12 kg plate.","[['CARDINAL', 3, 4], ['QUANTITY', 13, 15], ['ORDINAL', 18, 19], ['QUANTITY', 21, 23], ['QUANTITY', 38, 40]]"
351,S0167610512002292-3305.txt,"A uniform inflow condition is used, with the wind speed of 35 m/s (126 km/h) is used, which is within the range of full-scale failure wind speeds typically discussed by Visscher and Kopp (2007).","[['CARDINAL', 78, 79], ['QUANTITY', 83, 85], ['PERSON', 106, 107], ['PERSON', 108, 109], ['DATE', 110, 111]]"
352,S1873506114000075-1132.txt,The differentiation medium was changed to fresh medium 48 h before the assay.,"[['CARDINAL', 8, 9]]"
353,S2213671113001306-1404.txt,Animals were sacrificed and perfusion-fixed at 4 weeks posttransplantation and the recovered grafts then sectioned.,"[['DATE', 8, 10]]"
354,S2213671113001306-1404.txt,"Moreover, fetal and adult hRPE on PET carriers stained positively for the human-specific marker SC121, confirming survival of human RPE for 1 month as a monolayer (Figure 3).","[['ORG', 90, 91], ['DATE', 108, 110], ['CARDINAL', 115, 116]]"
355,S2213671113001306-1404.txt,"Costaining of SC121 with an antibody to MCT1 and Ezrin, both apical membrane markers, further confirmed that the RPE were (still) polarized (Figure 3).","[['PERSON', 125, 126], ['GPE', 127, 128], ['ORG', 138, 139], ['CARDINAL', 146, 147]]"
356,S2213671113001306-1404.txt,We estimated the total human RPE cell survival to be approximately 95% after 1 month by using the SC121 positivity; we measured the total length of the carrier and the length of SC121 stain and calculated the percent coverage of SC121 over the total carrier length.,"[['PERCENT', 200, 203], ['DATE', 204, 206]]"
357,S2213671113001306-1404.txt,These results confirm survival of polarized human RPE from fetal and adult donors xenografted into rabbit SRS over 4 weeks.,"[['ORG', 285, 286], ['DATE', 287, 289]]"
358,S0019103512004009-5271.txt,In Paper II we demonstrate that a mass loss rate of 6 × 106 kg s−1 is required to prevent diffusive separation of O (the heaviest neutral species detected so far) in the thermosphere.,"[['CARDINAL', 55, 56]]"
359,S0016236113008041-3161.txt,"For Na, Al, K and Fe, the lowest bed inventory of 4.5 kg resulted in a concentration in the flue gas which was less than that of the blank sample, values which then increased for the higher bed inventories.","[['QUANTITY', 14, 16]]"
360,S0016236113008041-3161.txt,"In the case of P, decreased values compared to the blank were found for bed inventories of 4.5 kg and 13 kg, but an increased value for 6 kg inventory.","[['QUANTITY', 91, 96], ['QUANTITY', 102, 104]]"
361,S0016236113008041-3161.txt,"However, the values are very low at <0.01 ppm and this anomalous result may be due to analytical errors.",[]
362,S0016236113008041-3161.txt,"Overall, although concentrations in the flue gas are small at <2 ppm, increasing bed inventory does appear to increase the concentration of the majority of major elements present in the flue gas.",[]
363,S2213671113001306-1520.txt,Longitudinal and transversal line OCT scans through the center of the implant were taken with the 30-degrees-of-visual-field setting of the Spectralis.,"[['QUANTITY', 51, 58], ['WORK_OF_ART', 63, 64]]"
364,S2213671113001306-1520.txt,Volume scans were obtained with 60 μm distance between each scan with the device set to 20 × 20 degrees of visual field centered on the implant.,"[['CARDINAL', 70, 71], ['CARDINAL', 81, 82], ['LOC', 82, 83], ['QUANTITY', 83, 85]]"
365,S2213671113001306-1520.txt,"To approximate human optical parameters to rabbit eyes, the Spectralis’ corneal curvature settings were set by default to 4.2 mm.","[['QUANTITY', 113, 115]]"
366,S2213671113001306-1520.txt,Red-free and infrared cSLO images were taken at 30 degrees of visual field in the HRA mode of the device.,"[['QUANTITY', 126, 128]]"
367,S0378383912000130-1048.txt,Results for the 1.5 mm beach.,"[['QUANTITY', 26, 28]]"
368,S0167880913001229-1304.txt,"The difference between management treatments is likely to be due to the application of organic fertilisers (at up to 11.25 Mg ha−1 year−1), as no significant differences were found between these subplot treatments for total inputs of above-ground biomass to the soil in the form of senescent leaf litter and pruned material (p = 0.24).","[['CARDINAL', 18, 20], ['CARDINAL', 20, 21], ['CARDINAL', 60, 61]]"
370,S0167880913001229-1304.txt,Both conventional and organic managements showed a consistent decline in SOC stocks at the two lower soil depths with no significant between-treatment differences (Fig. 3).,"[['ORG', 104, 105], ['CARDINAL', 108, 109], ['ORG', 120, 121], ['CARDINAL', 122, 123]]"
371,S0165587612003680-953.txt,A possible explanation for the discrepancy between high PCR-positive rate and low culture-positive rate in OME is the involvement of biofilms in the progression of this pathology [20].,"[['ORG', 19, 20], ['CARDINAL', 32, 33]]"
372,S0165587612003680-953.txt,"Indeed, biofilms have been identified on human middle ear mucosa in children with OME and/or recurrent AOM in more than 90% of cases, but not in any control samples studied [12].","[['ORG', 49, 50], ['ORG', 52, 53], ['PERCENT', 54, 58], ['CARDINAL', 69, 70]]"
373,S0165587612003680-953.txt,"In addition to tissue surfaces, biofilms have also been identified attached to mucus [21,22] and attach in vitro to collagen gel matrix [23].","[['CARDINAL', 98, 99]]"
374,S0165587612003680-953.txt,"In OME, biofilms may be attached to mucus as well as mucosa, thus providing the inflammatory stimulus leading to a middle ear effusion [10,13,24].","[['ORG', 102, 103], ['CARDINAL', 127, 128]]"
375,S0032063313003218-6651.txt,"We interpret our FAC density profiles by considering the corresponding precipitating electron energy fluxes, as shown in Fig. 6(b).","[['ORG', 3, 4], ['PERSON', 18, 19]]"
376,S0032063313003218-6651.txt,"The line style code and labels are the same as in Fig. 6(a), the latitudinal size of a HST ACS-SBC pixel is indicated by the dark grey rectangle and the grey solid line indicates the limit of present HST detectability (~1kR;","[['PERSON', 42, 43], ['CARDINAL', 44, 45]]"
377,S0032063313003218-6651.txt,"Cowley et al., 2007).","[['DATE', 84, 85]]"
378,S0032063313003218-6651.txt,"Therefore, we would expect a fairly bright auroral oval of ~88kR for case ES and ~79kR for case EF.","[['ORG', 159, 160], ['GPE', 164, 165]]"
379,S0032063313003218-6651.txt,Our model also predicts the possibility of observable polar emission (region II/I boundary) of ~15kR for both cases ES and EF.,"[['ORG', 219, 220], ['GPE', 221, 222]]"
380,S0022399913003358-931.txt,"However, subjective tinnitus is much more common and results from abnormal neural activities which are not formed by sounds [1].","[['CARDINAL', 64, 65]]"
381,S0022399913003358-931.txt,"Subjective tinnitus is a common and disturbing phenomenon, with a reported prevalence ranging from 7 to 20% [2–5] in the general population, and an estimated 10 year incidence rate in adults aged over 48 years of 13% [6].","[['PERCENT', 82, 86], ['DATE', 95, 99], ['DATE', 105, 107], ['PERCENT', 108, 110], ['CARDINAL', 111, 112]]"
382,S0022399913003358-931.txt,"Approximately 5% of the population is severely affected by their tinnitus [7], for example experiencing sleep disorders, concentration difficulties, and symptoms of anxiety and depression.","[['PERCENT', 114, 117]]"
383,S0927024813002420-1032.txt,"The performance and morphology of vacuum co-deposited BHJs was studied through variation of four main parameters—active layer thickness, polymer–fullerene composition and post-production thermal annealing temperature and time.","[['CARDINAL', 15, 16]]"
384,S0927024813002420-1032.txt,A series of initial experiments indicated that BHJ with 80 vol% of C60 and a thickness of 70 nm lead to device characteristics comparable to the previously reported planar heterojunction devices (Jsc∼2–3 mA/cm2 and Voc∼0.40–0.45 V),"[['ORG', 71, 72], ['CARDINAL', 73, 74], ['ORG', 76, 77], ['CARDINAL', 81, 82]]"
385,S0927024813002420-1032.txt,[37].,"[['CARDINAL', 105, 106]]"
386,S016412121300188X-4937.txt,20 shows individual SCGs for each version of barcode.,"[['CARDINAL', 49, 50]]"
387,S016412121300188X-4937.txt,The SCGs show that from the initial version barcode-0.90 there were two coherent clusters in the system.,"[['CARDINAL', 96, 97]]"
388,S016412121300188X-4937.txt,The smaller one is around 10% of the code while the larger is around 40% of the code.,"[['PERCENT', 107, 110], ['PERCENT', 117, 120]]"
389,S016412121300188X-4937.txt,"This is why in the later stages of the evolution we see an increase in the size of the largest cluster, but not the smaller one.",[]
390,S0012821X13002185-994.txt,"Biogenic silicon cycling is inextricably linked to both long and short term carbon cycling through the diatoms, siliceous walled autotrophs which today account for up to 40% of primary production.","[['DATE', 58, 59], ['PERCENT', 61, 65]]"
391,S0012821X13002185-994.txt,"At ODP site 1090 in the Southern Ocean, a 0.6‰ rise in diatom δ30Si through the late Eocene documents increasing diatom silicic acid utilisation with high, near modern values attained by the earliest Oligocene.","[['ORG', 146, 147], ['DATE', 148, 149], ['LOC', 150, 153], ['CARDINAL', 155, 156], ['PERSON', 163, 164], ['PERSON', 180, 181]]"
392,S0012821X13002185-994.txt,A concomitant 1.5‰ decline in sponge δ30Si at ODP site 689 on the Maud Rise tracks an approximate doubling of intermediate depth silicic acid concentration in the high southern latitudes.,"[['CARDINAL', 184, 185], ['ORG', 190, 191], ['CARDINAL', 192, 193]]"
393,S0012821X13002185-994.txt,"Intermediate depth silicic acid concentration peaked at ∼31.5 Ma, coincident with the final establishment of a deepwater pathway through the Tasman Gateway and Drake Passage.","[['DATE', 220, 221], ['FAC', 233, 236]]"
394,S2213671113001306-1398.txt,"In contrast, we found that all these negative effects were ameliorated through 1 to 2 mg intravitreal triamcinolone (TCA) injection at the end of the surgery.","[['CARDINAL', 78, 81], ['ORG', 85, 86]]"
395,S2213671113001306-1398.txt,Ophthalmic and systemic complications related to the implantation procedure are summarized in Table 2.,"[['LAW', 122, 124]]"
396,S0927775713009606-1361.txt,It is important to note that the divalent cation Cd2+ has an ionic radius of 0.097 nm,"[['CARDINAL', 16, 17]]"
397,S0927775713009606-1361.txt,"[22], which leads to a number of speculative points; (1) the diameter of the cation is smaller than the internal cavity of the amylose helix (double or single; ca.","[['CARDINAL', 19, 20], ['CARDINAL', 32, 33]]"
398,S0927775713009606-1361.txt,"0.4–1.0 nm), which itself is presumably flexible under the synthesis conditions to accommodate introduction of the Cd2+ into its hydrophobic cavity (perhaps occupying micropores (Table 1); (2) the diameter is also approximately the same length as the (OH) H-bonding distances (i.e. 0.19–0.21 nm)","[['LAW', 85, 87], ['CARDINAL', 90, 91], ['CARDINAL', 111, 112]]"
